字幕OCR lengshan310 压制 lengshan310
我叫索菲亚·克兰 今天是2004年3月3日
My name is Sophia Crane. It's March 3rd, 2004.
我是一个电影系学生 这是我的毕业论文
I'm a film student and this is my senior thesis.
我不知道我还能活多久
I don't know how much longer I'm going to be alive,
所以我请求找到这个人
so I ask whoever find this,
请把这个最后情景的前后两部分
please apply the first and second halves
分别剪辑到我的电影开头和结尾
of this final interview to the beginning and end of my film.
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know where to make the cut.
这是一个偷窥狂的故事
This is the story of Peeping Tom
以及我是如何寻找他的
and how I went looking for him.
请把这个给我父母看看
Please show this to my parents.
我不知道我还能坚持多久不眨眼
I don't know how much longer I can go without blinking.
早上好 伙计们 进来吧
Morning, fellas. Come on in.
这就是我告诉你们的那所房子
So, this is the house I was telling you about.
这是我老丈人的家
This is my in-laws' house.
我们只知道 似乎是在1970年到75年间建造的
The information that we have on it, it seems to have been built around 1970-75,
除了这个 我找不到其他的信息
I can't really find any information other than that,
但是在地下室
but down here in the basement
巴特就是在这找到的
is where Bart found it.
我来开灯 为了做这次的展示
I'll turn the light on. Now, I have repositioned it
我把它的位置重新调整了 你等我下
for presentation purposes so, if you'll bear with me...
在这 我去把它挖出来
Here, just going to go and dig it out.
现在如果你能看见我 它就在这下面
Right now if you can see me, it was right under here.
是这个盒子 过来 我给你看
It was this... box. Come over here, I'll show it to you.
写着别看
Don't watch, huh.
很诡异 但所有恐怖片不都是这么开始的吗?
Pretty eerie, but isn't that how all good horror movies start?
一个小秘密 一个小谜语
A little mystery, a little riddle.
我丈夫最近退休了
Well, my husband recently retired,
我想 在感恩节前
we find this beautiful house that we both loved
我们都找到了喜欢的漂亮房子
and I guess it was just before Thanksgiving.
我丈夫去了地下室 做了男人该做的事
My husband went down in the basement, did what guys do, you know,
检查锅炉 检查空调 检查过滤器 诸如此类的事情
check the boiler, check the air conditioning, play with the filters, things like that.
他发现这个盒子里装满了磁带
He found this box full of tapes.
他觉得加文可以把它们用在工作上
She thought that Gavin could use them for work,
因为他做婚礼录像
because he does wedding videos and
她想也许他可以用磁带录像 或者别的什么 为了省钱嘛
she thought maybe he can tape over them, or something, like to save money,
但是现在有迷你摄像机了 所以我们不再用了
but there are mini DVs so we don't really use them anymore.
我想也许加文可以看看这些磁带的内容
You know, I thought maybe Gavin can take a look at them, see what's on them,
搞一个小项目 让他保持对电影的兴奋
something as like a little project to keep him interested and excited about film.
我第一次看到的是
And the very first one that I picked up says:
最终解决方案
Final Solution.
这是我看的第一部
Alright, that's the first one I watched,
我是说 我怎么可能不看这样的东西呢?
I mean, how could you not watch anything like that, right?
那么最终解决方案这盒磁带上说的什么？
So what happened on the tape Final Solution, what did you see?
一个年轻的姑娘称自己是电影系学生索菲亚·克兰
A young lady identifies herself as Sophia Crane, a film student.
太巧合 我是电影专业 她也是电影专业
Total coincidence, as a film major, film major,
所以我们已经有些联系了 很不错
so already we're simpatico, which is great.
她对学校的项目很不高兴 她有一点压力
She's upset about the school project, she's stressed out a little bit,
然后在那之后变得有点沮丧 有点奇怪
and then it got a little upsetting after that and a little bit weird.
而且还变得暴力 我现在不想探讨那些内容
Some violence, some things that I don't really wanna say right now,
我们不能一次性都透露完了
we don't what to give it all away.
但是我们只能说我必须在那之后
But let's just say that I had to watch
马上看完接下来的40盘磁带
about the next 40 tapes immediately after that.
我做的第一件事就是给我们卖房子的前房主打电话
First thing I did was, of course, call the previous owner that we bought the house from,
在语音信箱里留言说 我找到了一个盒子
left voicemail messages saying that I found a box,
找到了一些可能是他们的东西
found something that probably belongs to them.
我没有收到他们的回复
I never heard back from them,
最后电话号码也变空号了
and then eventually the phone number was just unlisted.
但是这些镜头从来没有在你岳父母的家里取景
But the footage never actually takes place in your in-laws' house.
没有 这是另一个有趣的事了 让我变得很兴奋
No, it doesn't, and that's another kind of fun, clinky dink about this whole thing.
那你打算对这个房子怎么办呢？
What are you doing in regards to the home?
卖掉它
Selling it.
在第一盘磁带之后
After the first tape,
我看到的下一盘磁带叫做 粗略编辑
the next tape that I saw there was called Rough Edit.
一切看起来都很好 在街上有采访
Everything looks really good, there is interviews on the street,
非常顺畅 大约十分钟后 情况变得非常不稳定
really nice flow, and then after about ten minutes it gets really choppy.
里面大约有40盘磁带
And it's about 40 or so tapes in here,
他们忙得没时间剪辑
so it's like they got too busy to cut it together and they just kept
不停地拍啊拍 拍啊拍 不知道什么时候停下来
filming and filming and filming and they didn't really know when to stop.
- 你做了什么? - 作为一名优秀的电影制作人
- So what did you do? - Well, being a good filmmaker
我剪辑好他们的视频 完成了电影拍摄
as I am, I took their film and I finished it.
我自己编辑的
I edited it together myself, I took their film
我把他们的电影做成我的电影 现在它完成了
and made it my film, so now it's finished,
现在的样子才是它本身应该是的样子
now it's completed the way that it should have been.
你看到了完整版的影片之后 你是怎么想的?
And what did you think when you saw it all in sequence?
在那之后的几天
Well, I didn't really sleep
我都没有睡好
for a couple of days after that.
在我身后是伊尔切斯特隧道 巴尔的摩-俄亥俄铁路源发地 该死 再来一次
Behind me stands the Ilchester tunnel, home to the B&O... Shit, again.
开始了吗？
Are we rolling?
对我来说 它看起来...
Well, I mean, to me it looks it...
在我身后的是伊尔切斯特隧道 一个多世纪以来一直是巴铁的路段
Behind me stands the Ilchester tunnel, a thruway for the B&O Railroad for over a century.
但在过去的80年里 对当地居民来说 这已经变得更加危险
But for the past 80 years, for local residents, it has become something far more sinister.
它变成了...
It's become home to...
- 偷窥狂 - 偷窥狂
- Peeping Tom. - Peeping Tom.
- 眨眼的人 - 眨眼先生
- The Blink Man. - Mr. Blink.
- 偷窥狂汤姆 - 偷窥狂汤姆
- Peeping Tom. - Peeping Tom.
- 那个眨眼的人 - 伊尔切斯特性骚扰者
- The Blink Man. - The Ilchester The Molester.
隧道人
The Tunnel Guy?
- 偷窥狂 - 老色鬼
- Peeping Tom. - Old Blinky.
你们以前见过他吗？
Alright, so you guys have ever seen him before?
除非我现在是鬼 否则没见过
Unless I'm a ghost right now, then no!
如果我看见他 我就死定了
If I saw him, I'd be dead.
我认识一个人 跟我差不多大
Yes, I did know this one fellow around my age,
大概64 65岁 他看到了眨眼的人
this is back around 64-65 or so, he saw The Blink Man.
- 他怎么了？ - 嗯 他死了
- What happened to him? - Well, he died.
偷窥狂汤姆是一种你可以召唤的生物
Peeping Tom is the kind of creature that you can summon up,
有一种仪式 青少年朝圣什么的 午夜的公路旅行
so there is a ritual, those teen pilgrimages, you know, the midnight road trip,
午夜时分 你出现在隧道的尽头
you show up at the trestle end of the tunnel at midnight
你必须盯着这条隧道 看整整一个小时
and you have to stare down this tunnel, looking at the end for a full hour.
如果你能做到这一点 不眨眼
And if you can do this without blinking,
偷窥狂汤姆就会从阴影中走出来 出现在你面前
Peeping Tom comes out of the shadows and materializes in front of you.
他是一种超自然生物 被称为颤抖鬼
Now he's the class of supernatural creature called a Flimmern-Geist.
德国炼金术士在16世纪发明了这个术语
German alchemists came up with this term in the 1500s
指的是你在眼角看到的东西
for that thing, that you see in the corner of your eyes
但当你环顾四周 发现什么都没有
and when you look around to see it, there's nothing there.
偷窥狂汤姆实际上
Peeping Tom is a Flimmern-Geist
是你可以看到的一个颤抖鬼
that you can actually bring into view.
- 嗯 他又高又黑 - 皮包骨头
- Well, he's tall, dark coat. - Skinny.
- 高帽子 - 吓人的大眼睛
- Top hat. - Big scary eyes.
大多数时候我听说他只是个影子
Mostly I've heard that he's just a shadow,
因为他就像你的周边视觉
'cause he's like in your peripheral vision.
瞬间在那里 然后不在那里 然后又在那里
Instantly there, then not there, then there again.
有个小妞 几年前
There was this one chick, in particular,
她在这条路上的一所学校上学
a few years ago, she went to the school right down the road.
她和她的朋友们走到隧道轨道上
Her and her friends went up to the tunnel rail
他们开始凝视 她是唯一一个可以凝视那么久的人 因为你得不眨眼凝视
and they started staring down, she was the only one who could stare for... you have to stare
- 一个小时 - 一个小时
- for an hour. - For an hour.
奇怪的是
The twist is that
一旦你看到了他 就无法无视他
once you've seen him, you can't unsee him.
每次你眨眼的时候 他就会更近一些
Every time you blink, he's a little bit closer
每次你眨眼 他就会越来越近 直到他的脸出现在你的面前
and he comes closer and closer each time you blink until he's right in your face.
他听起来很可怕 他做了什么？
He sounds scary, what does he do?
- 得到你 - 得到你
- Gets you. - Gets you.
现在你已经证明了
And now you've already proved
你可以很长一段时间都睁着眼
that you can keep your eyes open
不闭上
for a long time,
那就是召唤他的方法
because that's how you conjure him up.
当他出现的时候
When he's right up there,
死亡就在眼前的那种诱惑让你无法抗拒
the temptation is death staring you in the face,
你要尽一切可能避开他
you do anything you can to avoid him.
但是他有一个诡计
But he's got a trick up his sleeve,
他有很长的睫毛
he has very long eyelashes
你知道吧 你对小婴儿会这么做
and you know that thing that you do with babies,
在他们面前这样弄一弄 他也会这样对你
to give them a little, he does that,
然后你就忍不住了 眨眼了 我们怎么叫的...
and then you can't help it, you blink. What do we call that...
我能展示一下吗 鬼...
Can I show it, like... Butterfly...
...鬼眨眼
...butterfly kisses.
我很确定 其实也说不好
I'm pretty sure there's only, I don't know,
世界上只有几个人
a couple of people in the world, period,
可以直盯一个小时
that can stare for an hour straight.
好像是世界纪录还是什么 是不是一小时
I think the world record, I don't even know if the world record is an hour.
我想纪录大概是30分钟 40分钟
I think the record is probably maybe 30 minutes, 40 minutes.
盯着一样东西不眨眼10到15分钟真的很难
It's really hard to stare at something without blinking
这对大多数人来说真的很难
for even 10 or 15 minutes. It will be really difficult for most people.
当然了 没有任何纪录 人民忙于死亡而无暇报道
Well, of course, there's no record of it. People too busy dying to report it.
即使你坚持了那么长时间 我的意思是你的视力会变得很模糊
Even if you made it out to that long, I mean the vision will be quite blurred and, again,
我怎么强调都不过分 疼痛会非常折磨人
you know, I can't emphasize enough, the pain would be excruciating.
就像所有最棒的民间传说和都市传说一样
As with all the best folklore and urban legends,
你无法核实其中的任何细节
you can't really verify any of the details in this.
这种事总是发生在朋友的朋友身上
It's always happened to a friend of a friend.
我哥哥的朋友过去常讲他叔叔给他讲的故事
My brother's friend used to tell the story that his uncle told him.
过了一会儿 他们吓坏了 跑掉了
And they got freaked out after a while and they ran away
但她在那里呆了整整一个小时
but she did stay there the whole hour.
大约一个月后 他们发现他的尸体
Like a month later they found his body
漂在帕塔普斯科河上
floating in the Patapsco River.
最后她试着往窗外看
She ended up trying to look out a window,
她试着通过直视太阳...
she tried to burn out her eyes...
烧掉她的眼睛
By looking at the sun.
虽然她看不见他
Even though she couldn't see him,
但他仍然存在
his presence was still there
所以她 你知道 她一直在想 她会眨眼
so she, you know, she thought the whole time, she gets blinks,
总是会眨的 但是她...
she ended up blinking, but she...
她能打败偷窥狂汤姆吗？
Can she beat Peeping Tom?
- 不过 不能作弊 - 不能欺骗偷窥狂汤姆
- Can't cheat, though. - Can't cheat Peeping Tom.
我认为这是在
You know, I think you'd be pushing the limits, I think,
挑战人类解剖学和生理学的极限
of the human anatomy and physiology,
但也许这毕竟是可能的
but maybe that's possible.
很明显 从他给我分享的经历来讲
Obviously, from he shared with me,
如果这是真的 那可真是个很糟糕的主意
that would be a terrible idea, if that's for real.
缺乏证据并不是缺乏信念的原因
Absence of proof hasn't caused absence of belief.
伊彻斯特隧道仍然是青少年深夜出没的地方
Ilchester tunnel is still a late night hang out for teenagers
也是兄弟会欺辱的热门场所
and a popular spot for fraternity hazing.
这是一个经常有人去 但显然很少完成的挑战 直到现在
It's a dare often attempted, but apparently seldom completed. Until now.
午夜时分 你出现在隧道尽头
You show up at the trestle end of the tunnel at midnight...
磁带上的数据显示
The metadata on the tapes
这段视频拍摄于
show that it was filmed between February 14th
2004年2月14日至3月3日之间
and March 3rd of 2004.
我回去看了看当地所有的大学
OK, so I went back and I looked at all of the local colleges,
我打了电话 我走进镇上的每一所大学
I called, I walked into every college in town,
给他们看了索菲亚的照片 给他们看了费德曼的照片
showed them pictures of Sophia, showed them pictures of Feldman.
没有任何信息 你根本搞不定这些人
No information. You can't get past these people at all.
没有记录显示沃尔夫博士的任何信息 据称她是他们的导师
There's no record of a doctor Wolfe who's supposedly their professor,
也没有迹象表明索菲亚和费德曼
there's no indication that the Peeping Tom specialist that Sophia and Feldman
登门拜访的那位偷窥狂专家真实存在
go and speak to in his home even exists,
而那个亚裔美国人 我相信他应该是个眼科专家
an Asian American man, I believe he's supposed to be an eye specialist.
数据库中没有信息显示该人的存在
There's no title cards to show that this person even exists.
我分析了他们 反复观察他们
I analyzed them, and I watched them repeatedly, I looked back on
我回顾了每一个我能找到的与这些人匹配的事件
every incident reported I could find that would have matched
但我找不到任何匹配的
any of these people, and I can't find anything that matches up.
我的看法是 他可能只是碰巧发现了一些学生电影
My hunch would say he probably found either some student films
或者有人自己制作恐怖电影 或者其他什么
or just somebody making her own horror movie or something like that.
没有剪辑 没有重拍 没有要求采取行动
There's no cuts, there's no retakes, there's no calling for action,
除了电影的前两分钟
aside from the first two minutes of the movie,
索菲亚显然是在自己导演
where Sophia is obviously directing herself,
绝对没有证据表明有人在指挥他们
there's absolutely no evidence to suggest that somebody is directing them.
我已经盯着它看了六个月了
I've been staring at it for the better part of six months right now.
我相信这百分之百是事实
I believe it's 100% genuine.
看起来像是旧片重制罢了
It looks like found footage.
- 电影   - 对
- Movie. - Alright.
旧片重制 我是说
Found footage, I mean,
这到底是什么意思呢？
what does that really mean?
我有找到什么录像吗？
Did I find the footage?
是有人交给我这些东西然后我再展示？ 如果是的话
Was it handed to me and then am I presenting it again? Yes.
那确实叫做旧片重制
That would be considered found footage,
但就恐怖电影来说
but as far as putting a horror movie together,
我真的不认为...
I don't really think that there's any...
我是一个优秀的电影制作人
I'm a, I'm a real filmmaker.
我们不会制作恐怖电影
OK, so we're not gonna be making horror movies.
我们做的是去揭示一些神秘事物的真相
We're gonna try to reveal the truth of something
或者从中发现一些东西
that's a mystery or kind of get something out of it.
当你制作的电影
When you make a film that is presenting itself
呈现的不过是一个粗略剪辑的片段时
as roughly cut together found footage,
你可以为任何有问题的地方找借口
you are building in your excuse for anything that's wrong with it.
伙计们 这是我们找到的录像 我们只是在展示
Uh, hey folks, this is the footage we found, we're just presenting it, yeah.
相机到处晃动 不是因为我们不知道如何保持手持相机的稳定
The camera jiggles all over the place, not because we didn't know how to hold
而是因为这些在森林里迷路的孩子
a hand-held camera steady, but because these were kids lost in the woods
变得越来越害怕
getting more and more scared all the time.
我认为 如果这是第一部
I think what would make it more real,
没有被划分到任何一种类型去的电影的话
would be if it were the first one out there
会让它更真实
and they were not following a certain genre.
就低预算水平来说确实不错
It works on a low-budget level
而低预算也正是该类电影出现的主要原因
and that's the primary reason for, I think, for doing it.
所以我的观点是 要么约克先生自己自导自演了这一切
So my hunch is either Mr. York was doing that himself
试图获得一些证据 让它看起来更真实
and trying to get some credence to this and make it look legitimate,
要么他只是运行别人的项目 然后他们把它发出来
or he just run somebody else's project and they send it through.
我们都很清楚 他找不到学生
Just so we're all clear, the reason that he can't find the students,
老师 眼科医生的原因
the teachers, the eye doctor...
我认为他们是演员
I believe they're actors.
你会意识到 除了评论家们给你的作品打上“欺骗性”标签之外
You realize that the first thing that critics will accuse you of,
他们可能还会指责你自己伪造了这部电影
after gullibility, is faking the film yourself.
当然 当然 这就是为什么没有人会相信
Of course, of course, and that's why nobody would believe this.
因为发现这部未完成的电影的人
Because it's a pretty big coincidence
恰好是电影制作人
that the person who finds the unfinished film
这是一个很大的巧合
just happens to be a filmmaker.
当然 反对者会这么说因为他们的工作就是
Right, sure, and the naysayers are gonna say that
给别人提各种反对意见
because that's what they do, they naysay.
嗯 我不知道这是真的还是假的 但没关系
Hum, I don't know if it's real or not, but it doesn't really matter,
因为他对这是真的很兴奋 所以
because he's excited about it being real, so...
我们会把这段录像带给城里所有能找到的专业人士
We're gonna take this footage to every professional in town that we can find,
流言终结者协会 我们会去电台
ghosthunters, mythbusters, we're going to go to the radio stations,
我们要去电视台 我们要播放录像
we're going to the TV stations, we're going to show the footage and we're gonna saturate
我们会用这些信息充斥整个电影市场
the market with this information.
如果你的计划是证明这段视频的真实性
If your plan is to try to present this as being 100% authentic,
为什么你不直接带上原始片段 马上召开一个新闻发布会呢？
why are you not simply taking the footage forward and calling a press conference right now?
你为什么要把视频处理好 为什么要把声效做好呢？
Why are you planning to have the video cleaned up, why are you looking to have the sound done?
你知道 我们需要尽我们所能地呈现最好的版本
Well, I mean, you know, we need to present the best possible version of this thing as we can,
然后我们要向世界证明偷窥汤姆的所在
then we're gonna prove to the world that Peeping Tom exists.
相机不会说谎
The camera doesn't lie.
我是梅尔·萨姆纳 19岁 政治学专业学生 凝视比赛冠军
Mel Sumner, 19, PolySci major and staring contest champion.
好了 伙计 这后面是伊尔切斯特隧道
Alright, dude, so right down there is Ilchester tunnel
我们会让你站在那边的高架上
and we're gonna have you standing right over there
从12点开始 持续一个小时
on the other of the trestle, starting at 12 for an hour.
那么 我到底该看什么？
Well, how the hell am I supposed to see at the end of that?
你们别担心
Y'all, just don't worry about it.
- 你准备好了吗？ - 是的 开始吧
- You ready? - Yes, let's stare at it.
好吧 离午夜还有10秒 开始
Alright, ten seconds to midnight starting... now.
- 感觉怎么样？ - 太催眠了
- What's it feels like? - It's so hypnotic!
你真的看不到那的任何东西
You literally, you can't really see anything down there.
我能看到
I can see.
这太可怕了 就像隧道也在盯着我一样
That's so creepy, it's like the tunnel's like staring right back at me.
这有点像终极凝视比赛 你知道的
This is kind of like the ultimate staring contest, you know, like...
即使我赢了 我也不能再眨眼了
even if I win, I can never really blink again.
我们有多少时间？
How much, how much time we're at?
- 加油 伙计 - 你能行的 伙计
- Come on, dude! - You got it, man!
别和我说话
Please stop talking to me.
- 索菲亚 闭嘴         - 别说话了
- Sophia, shut up. - Stop talking.
你没事吧？
You're alright?
妈的 我的天
Fuck! Oh, God!
你为什么想要数码相机？
Why do you want Handycam?
我们用我们的好相机来纪录这个
We're using our good camera to document this,
我想要拍下那个 好吗？
I wanna be able to document that, OK?
你知道这段录像和你想象的完全不一样 对吧？
You realize the footage will come nowhere close to matching up, right?
这是纪录片 伙计 不一定要完全一样
It's documentary, dude, it doesn't have to match.
我不理会你刚才说的话
I'm gonna ignore that you just said that.
我们现在要做的是设置这个摄像头
So, what we're doing now is we set up this camera,
我要从午夜开始在隧道里拍摄
I'm gonna shoot it down the tunnel
一直到凌晨1点
starting right at midnight, it's gonna go all the way to 1:00 a.m.
- 好吧 - 现在它将取代人眼
- Yeah. - Now this will take the place
它不会眨眼
of a human eye and it will not blink,
它会一直运行 希望就在凌晨1点
it will constantly run and hopefully right at 1:00 a.m.,
就像传说中的 偷窥狂汤姆会出现
as the legend says, Peeping Tom will show up
对我的相机进行鬼眨眼
and butterfly kiss my camera.
听着 尽管我很讨厌这么说
Look, as much as I hate to say this
但我认为这样做可能真的不行
I think this actually has a really good shot of working
因为什么来着...？
before you let this go to your head
镜头就是一双眼睛 不是吗？
simply because a lens is like an eye, OK?
- 快门 我们好了  - 快门？
- The shutter, we're good, OK? - The shutter?
是快门 从技术层面来说
Yes, I think the shutter. Well, technically...
这不过是相机的一个部件
That's the only part of the camera...
从技术上讲 这就相当于人眨眼 你说啥？
Technically, that would be blinking. The what?
好了 伙计 我们马上就开始了
Alright, man, we're coming up on it.
- 几点了？ - 你准备好了吗？
- What's the time? - You ready?
几点了？
What's the time?
我们还有十秒钟的时间
We've got ten more seconds
现在开始
starting now.
十   九...
Ten, nine...
眨眼先生 看到什么了吗？
Come on, Mr. Blink, See anything?
- 没有 没看到  - 继续
- No, nothing. - Come on!
现在 时间到了
And, now!
看到什么了吗？
See anything?
别关相机 你看到什么了吗？
Don't kill it! You see anything?
你看到什么了吗？
Do you see anything?
费德曼 回答我的问题 你看的什么了吗？
Feldman, answer my question, do you see anything?
不要关相机 给他点时间
Do not kill the camera, just give him a second to...
妈的
Fuck!
...你住的地方 但是如果我要整理的话 得把这里清理一下
...that you live in, but if I'm gonna be here to yada yada, clean this up a little bit,
这些磁带 我能不能弄个盒子
I mean, as far as the tapes go, can I make like a box, like the...
- 好的  - 你拿一个鞋盒 或者...
- OK. - You got a shoe box , or...
我们改天再来解决这个问题
We'll just work on this another day.
我们有后备计划吗？
Do we have a backup plan here?
伙计 伙计 伙计 你看到了吗？
Dude, dude, dude, dude! Are you seeing that?
我看到什么了吗？
Am I seeing what?
费德曼 看这里
Feldman, look right there!
- 我知道 - 你看见了吗？
- Yeah! I know. - Do you see that?
什么？ 是在那里还是...
What? Was that there or...
你看到了吗？那是什么鬼东西？
Do you see that? What the fuck is that?
- 我没加上去  - 你是认真的吗？
- I didn't add it! - Are you serious?
- 哦 我的天哪 我想...  - 天哪
- Oh, my gosh, I think... - Holy shit!
有没有什么办法能让它更亮一点
Is there any way that you can brighten this, like whatsoever.
是啊 是啊 虽然成果可能不咋地 但是我能做到
Yeah, yeah, I mean it's gonna look like hell, but no, I can do it.
好吧 你想让我现在就拿相机吗？
OK, do you want me to take the camera right now?
我要把灯打开
So, I'm bringing up the light.
酷 酷 打开吧
Cool, cool, do it!
- 天哪 伙计 - 对了
- Gosh, dude! - Bang!
就他妈的在那儿
Right fucking there!
那正好是报时时间
That was right on the hour mark.
放大 放大
Zoom in, zoom in.
好了 这是我能做到的最接近的了
Alright, this is the closest I can get with that,
还能看到那个鬼东西 准备好了吗？
and like still be able to see shit, so you ready?
好了 好了 开始吧
Alright, alright, go, go!
-天哪 - 哦 我的天哪
- Holy shit! - Oh, my gosh!
看看那个混蛋
Look at that motherfucker!
你在跟我开玩笑
You're kidding me!
五分钟前 一切都结束了
Like five minutes ago, this is all over,
但是我们看到了偷窥狂汤姆
but we have Peeping Tom here!
- 我们他妈的看到了他 伙计 - 哦 我的天哪
- We fucking got him, man! - Oh my gosh!
我看不出有任何迹象表明它是伪造的 或者说...
I don't see any signs that it was faked, in the sense that like it was...
看不出有人用电脑技术加入了一些东西
like someone went in with a computer and added something,
没有什么东西可以明确地指出
like there's nothing in there that I can definitively point to and say:
好吧 这是假的
"OK, this is a fake."
所以 我想说的是
So, I would go with that,
与此同时 你也知道
at the same time, you know,
这是一个很小的视频
it's a small little video,
没有太多的细节
there's not a lot of detail,
所以我对这两种说法都不太确定
so I'm hesitant to commit either way,
但是我 如果...
but I, if it was...
如果有什么东西在那里  实况可能正是展示的这样
if something were there, it would probably look like that.
就这个镜头而言
You were convinced that that would just
敢肯定的是 这是自然光线下的结果 而不是对特定镜头的操纵
be natural lighting, no manipulation as far as that particular shot is concerned.
我不相信任何事 这当然是可能的
Well, I'm not convinced of anything, it's certainly plausible.
对 但你不排除这种可能性
Right, but you're not ruling it out.
我不能指着任何东西说
I can't point to anything and say:
这是假的
"This makes is a fake."
可能是一个人 穿着衣服
It could be a guy, dressed up,
也许是站在后面了
standing up in the back maybe,
可能是一场恶作剧
like, you know, it could be a practical kind of hoax,
可能是有人拿这个片段用电脑加工了
like someone could have taken this and in a computer,
操纵画面什么的
it's gone and manipulated it.
镜头等同于眼睛的这个想法可不行
The idea of the technological equivalent of the actual eye,
眼睛是人类有机体的一部分
which is actually a part of the human organism,
至于人类的大脑 将照相机作为与之真正等同的东西
and the human mind, the idea of using a camera as a real equivalent of that,
形而上的等同物的想法 让我觉得很难接受
metaphysical equivalent, strikes me as... I have a hard time with that.
我不知道 伙计 你 我是说我们坐在这里试图解释鬼魂 所以
I don't know, man, you, I mean we're sitting here trying to explain spirits, so...
如果你想理性地讨论一下
If you want to have a rational conversation about ghosts
鬼怪和半兽人与摄像技术的区别 我不太确定适不适合
and goblins versus camera technology, I'm not really sure.
我们在哪里？我们要做什么？
So, where are we? What are we doing?
我们现在在马里兰州格伦伯尼的一个兴趣小组
We are at the VFW in Glen Burnie, Maryland,
我要去给一群超自然现象调查人员
and I'm gonna go and present some of the footage to an assembled group
展示一些视频 在这里找一些盟友
of paranormal investigators, ghosthunters and get some allies here.
今晚的重头戏是什么？
What's the end game here tonight?
重头戏就是当我们做新闻发布会的时候
Well, the end game is that when we do the press conference,
我可以让几个人站在我旁边说
I can have a handful of these people standing beside me saying:
镜头是真实的
"Footage is real,
我们支持你 加文 我们相信你
we're behind you, Gavin, we believe you!"
然后他们 我想大概有10000人左右 所以
And then they... I think they reach some 10,000 people or something, so...
我们的脸书页面有超过8000个粉丝
Our Facebook page has over 8,000 likes
其中大多数人喜欢超自然现象
and most of those people
有些人想登上我们的脸书主页
are into the paranormal or they want to be on our Facebook page.
我可以把帖子放在那里让别人看
So, yes, I could put it out there for others to see.
我们来展示偷窥狂汤姆来到隧道的镜头
We're just gonna show the image of Peeping Tom coming up to the tunnel.
给他们看鬼魂的话为什么不把全部证据都展示出来？
Why are you only showing the ghost and apparently the ghost proofs?
只需要那一个镜头就足够了
Just that one shot.
我认为他们不需要任何其他信息
I don't think they need any of the other information,
我认为现在我们只是想确定
I think right now we're just trying to determine whether
偷窥狂汤姆是否是一个真实的存在
or not Peeping Tom is a real entity and the story about
以及索菲亚和其他人的故事及真实情况 大家对这个感兴趣的
Sophia and the big guns and on the actual what happened. I think you want to see that.
你们和我能想到的唯一合理的解释
The only plausible explanation that you folks could think
以及我想到的第一件事
and myself and the first thing I thought of
是这一定是一个穿西装的人
was this has got to be a guy in a suit,
这是一个站在隧道尽头的人
this is somebody standing there at the end of the tunnel,
他们在玩一个恶作剧 是吗？
they're playing a practical joke, OK?
然而 这个理论的错误之处在于
The thing that this bunks that theory however is the fact that the metadata
两个摄像头上的元数据都显示那里没有其他人
on both cameras say that there was no one else there.
一个摄像头拍另一个摄像头 我们有证据证明
One camera films the other camera, we've got proof of both of that
这两个摄像头都打开了 这是回放时发生的事情
it turned on, this is what happens when they played it back.
现在你需要引起每个人的兴趣 我们要让他们开始议论
Right now you just want to pick everybody's interest, we're gonna get them to talk,
谁是偷窥狂汤姆 隧道又是怎么回事？要充斥你的大脑
"Who's Peeping Tom, the tunnel?" Right here in your mind. Just phew!
你们怎么看他的展示
Gonna get it so he showed you.
在他向我们展示更多之前 我们不能确定
Until he shows us more, we just don't know.
- 说得对 - 我们相信有这种可能性
- Right! - We believe there's a possibility,
但我们需要更多的证据
but we need more evidence.
接下来的一步将会是沃尔夫的重大发现
Saying everything else for, you know, that next big steps will be wolf's surprise.
可能会有更好的结果
It'll probably work out a lot better too.
你可以看到我看到的
So you know, you can see what I saw.
我们已经开始的旅程
I mean the journey that we've already been on.
你不能说这是不可能的
You can't tell that this isn't gonna be the shot,
这是加文的机会 这也是我第二次机会
this is Gavin's chance, this is my second chance to make it.
财富和荣耀
Fortune and glory!
让我们回顾一下
Let's go back a little bit,
让我们以电影制作人的身份来谈谈你的看法吧
let's talk about you as a filmmaker.
你上学是为了拍电影？
You went to school for filmmaking?
是的 我没有学位 这就是我想告诉大家的
Yeah, my non-degree, that's what I like to tell everybody it was.
他做过很多婚礼视频 你知道 有结婚季
He does a lot of weddings, so, you know, there's wedding season
淡季的时候收入就有点不稳定了
and then in the off season it's kind of a little bit more spotty.
随着时间的流逝
And then as the years went by,
这成为了一种支付账单的方式 同时也让自己相信自己是一名电影制作人
it became a way to pay the bills and to still convince myself that I'm a filmmaker.
现在 这只是一种支付账单的方式
Now, it's just a way to pay the bills.
现在不是结婚季吗？
Isn't this wedding season right now?
现在是七月
Yeah, it's July.
对不起 我不想让任何人难堪 但是
I'm sorry, I don't want to embarrass anybody, but it...
她总是风风火火的 总是来借钱
She's always hectic, she's always happened to come and borrow money and,
这也不让我烦恼 这也是我们来这里的目的
and that doesn't bother me, that's what we're here for, right,
确保一切都是...
to make sure that everything's...
确保我们可以帮忙 一切都顺利
We can help out. Everything's OK.
加文知道你有去别处寻求帮助吗？
Does Gavin know that you're getting help?
反正我寻求的所谓帮助
I mean it's not so much help
也不是很多 所以没有提过
that it needs to be discussed or whatever.
我问你一个问题 你要拍他们的电影
So, let me ask you a question, you're taking their film
and you're trying to show it to the world,
但是你为什么不像我一样干我正在做的事情吗？
but why aren't you making this movie that I'm making right now?
你为什么不拍一部自己的电影
Why aren't you doing a film of your own essentially rather than just,
而不是把别人的拍完？
you know, taking somebody else's and finishing it?
如果我这么做 没人会相信的 好吗？
Nobody would believe this if I did it, OK?
没人会相信一部关于我寻找素材
Nobody's gonna believe a documentary about me finding footage
并将其组合起来而且为此四处奔波的纪录片
and putting it together and running around.
这就是我们需要你的原因 这就是你来这里讲述这个故事的原因
That's why we need you, that's why you're here to tell the story.
因为如果观众不相信这段录像 那么你的境遇也和我一样了
Because if the audience doesn't believe the footage, then you're in the same exact place.
进来
Come in!
伙计们
Fellas!
- 我是加文 你好吗？ - 你好吗？加文·约克
- Gavin, how are you doing? - How are you? Gavin York.
我想要确保
I want to make sure
这是经过深思熟虑的
that this is well thought out,
我们会认真对待
put together with a lot of care.
我们从事这个行业是因为我们喜欢娱乐大众
We're in this business because we like to entertain,
是因为我们想赚钱 明白吗？
but we're in this business because we want to make money, OK?
我理解 这是一种旧片重制的镜头风格
It's found footage, I understand, it's a found footage style.
好吧 但这是真实的 我确实找到了素材
Well, it's real. As in "It's found footage, because I found the footage."
- 好的   - 真的是我找到的
- OK. - I actually found it.
- 好的  - 好吧
- Right. - OK.
但你明白为什么它看起来可疑对吧
But you understand why it looks suspicious
因为你不只是单纯把原始镜头放在那里
that rather than just putting the footage out there,
你已经把它处理过了 混合过了
you are having it cleaned up and mixed
并且发行了出来
for theatrical release.
但是谁会知道呢？
But who is gonna know that?
而你现在把它当电影看
You're treating it right now like a movie.
但你为什么不能两者兼得呢？
But why can't you treat it both?
处理原始材料有点与这些视频的
Cleaning it up kind of defeats the purpose
粗糙质感这一初衷违背了
of it being this gritty found footage found in a basement.
我的意思是 我并不是真的想四处跑然后说
I guess, I mean I'm not really trying
嘿 看看它有多粗糙
to walk around and say, "Hey, look how gritty it is!"
这是你的项目
It's your project.
一切都归结于如何去做
It all comes down to how to approach it
当我们决定好的时候
and when we figure out how we're gonna approach it,
我们可以帮你做预算
then we can help you budget for it.
- 当然 - 我知道这是个问题
- Sure. - I understand that
我知道这不是很有趣
that's a concern. I understand that it isn't so fun.
- 是的 但是关于那个 - 在这个项目中
- Yeah, yeah, but about that... - In the project...
说实话 你能负担得起多少？
Realistically, how much can you afford?
实际上 我什么也买不起
Realistically, I can't afford anything.
这对我们来说是一个从底层突破的机会
This is an opportunity for us to get in like on the ground floor.
这是一个转折点 当你看的时候 你就会知道
This is a game changer. When you watch it, you will know.
你想让它们被这么操作
You're trying to get them to do this...
基本是免费 没有人工
For free, for zero, for a piece of the pie.
我们都知道这些对话经常发生
We all know these conversations happen all the time and in the reality of it is that,
而事实上 作为一项业务
as a business, there's got to be some kind of
必须有某种对我们有效的流程 好让我们付得起电费
process that works for us that keeps our lights on
- 是这个理 - 哦 当然 当然
- so to speak. - Oh, sure, sure.
如果我必须付钱
If I have to pay,
我愿意付1500美元
I'm willing to go maybe $1,500.
我们大概会卖
We could probably do about
2000美元 但之后只能吃拉面了
$2,000, but then it's gonna be a lot of ramen noodles.
大多数服务都涵盖了各种内容 即使是独立电影的收益也是10%到20%
Most features that get full packages, even on an indie rate are anywhere from like 10 to 20.
不谈成这件事我是不会离开的
I can't leave here without them agreeing to do this.
好吧 费德曼 让我来谈 好吗？
Alright, Feldman, just let me do the talking, OK?
- 没问题 - 谢谢
- Sure! - Cool! Thank you!
- 嗨 沃尔夫导师？ - 克兰小姐
- Hey, Dr. Wolfe? - Miss Crane.
嘿 我知道我来的时候太早了
Hey, I know it's first thing early in the morning and everything,
但是我们有一些很棒的
but we have something really awesome
纪录片要给你看 如果你能够...
to show you for the documentary and it would be great...
哇哦 费德曼先生 相机是怎么回事？
Wow, wow. Mr. Feldman, what's with the camera?
我来说 费德曼
I got this, Feldman.
实际上是为了纪录片
It's actually for the documentary.
我们要给你们看一些东西
There's actually something that we need to show you.
嘿 费德曼 你在放吗？
Hey, Feldman, are you rolling?
是的
Yeah.
这一切只是发生在五秒钟内
All this will become very clear in five seconds,
但我们把整个过程都纪录下来了
but we are documenting this entire process.
就在凌晨1点发生的
So, right at 1 a.m. this is what happened.
- 嗯 - 如何？
- Hmm. - So?
- 做得好 - 你怎么看？
- Nicely done! - What do you think?
这个特效很好 你们做的不错
An excellent effect! You guys have done a good job!
不 沃尔夫博士 这不是做的效果 这是真的
No, Dr. Wolfe, this is not an effect, this is for real!
你之前和我说的不是这么回事
This is not the project we talked about,
但是你现在手上的材料不错
but you've got a nice premise here,
你可以再好好加把劲加点别的
you've got something you can work with,
把它变成一部非常出色的恐怖片
you can turn this into a very sweet horror film.
- 我们 - 等一下 好吗？
- We... - Just one second, OK?
我的相机快没电了
My camera it's about run out of batteries.
好的 请把相机拿过来 这是灰色数据 沃尔夫博士
OK, get the camera, please. OK, this is grey data, Dr. Wolfe.
我们现在需要你的建议 好吗？
We need your advising right now, OK? This...
你想拍的这部心理剧
...psychodrama you're trying to do here
我尊重你 你想要有创意
and I respect, you're trying to be creative and all,
但我对你拍我感到很不舒服
but I'm very uncomfortable with you filming me.
我们根本没时间去做什么特效
There would not have been enough time to put all these
或者其他什么的
enhancements in it and everything else.
这家伙也不懂什么技术
This guy doesn't know what the hell he's doing.
费德曼 五分钟再回来吧
Take five, Feldman.
听着 我不会拿我的好名声冒险
Look, I would not put my good name on the line.
从你离开隧道的那一刻起
Did you have that tape in your hands
你每天24小时都拿着那盘带子吗？
24/7 from the moment that you walked away from that tunnel?
费德曼是个懒鬼 他六年的学业计划已经进行到了第七年了
Feldman is a slacker, he's in the seventh year of his six-year plan
但他是一个天才 你知道吗？
to get through school and, you know what? He's a genius.
在拿相机做事时
He's a genius when it comes to the camera
他就是一个天才
and doing things with it.
我给民俗通先生打了电话
Well, I called Mr. Folklore
在他的电话上留了言
and left a message on his machine,
所以我想我们应该
so I guess we should
先和他谈谈
have talked to him first.
我们为什么不现在就去找他呢？
Well, why don't we just go talk to him now?
我不能理解的是 有人怎么看了一眼这段录像
My big thing is how did anybody look at that footage
就说它不是真的？
and say that it's not real?
我也是这样想啊 我们自己都还在消化
That's what I'm saying. Obviously, we're still learning.
这东西根本就没办法造假
Like, you just can't fake that.
- 快啊  - 有回答吗？
- Come on! - Anything?
- 没有 - 那可太棒了
- No! - Awesome!
我去旁边看看
I'm gonna check the side.
老实说 我觉得爬进他的窗户有点怪 但是
Honestly, I feel a little weird about creeping in his window, but...
他自己就是个怪咖 我敢说你爬他的窗根本不算什么
This is a folklore guy, I'm sure this is the least creepy thing about it.
嗯
Yeah.
- 有发现吗？ - 没有
- Anything? - No!
该死 现在怎么办？
Shit! Now what?
1527号？
1527?
哦 是这个 是这个 就在这
Oh, this is it, this is it, right here.
各位 就是这所房子
You guys, this is the house.
哦 天哪
Oh, my God.
就像在梦里一样 我不敢相信我们真的在这里
Just like being in a dream, I can't believe we're actually here.
毫无疑问 我的整个写作生涯都是围绕这些“古怪系列”小说来的
It was undoubtedly through the Weird books that I have worked on for a good...
我花了7-8年的时间写了这一系列“怪异”丛书
It was about 7-8 years I was working on this series of Weird books
当然宾夕法尼亚州和马里兰州的那几本
and certainly in Pennsylvania and Maryland,
是我最出名的作品
this is what I'm best known for.
- 雷克先生 - 约克先生
- Mr. Lake! - Mr. York!
- 叫我加文 拜托了 - 加文
- Call me, Gavin, please! - Gavin.
这是摄制组和大家
This is the camera crew and everybody!
嗨  来吧
Hi! Come on...
别理他们
Just don't pay them any mind,
他们会做他们该做的事
they're just gonna do their thing.
- 好的 - 这个地方真棒
- OK. - This place is great!
我得告诉你 这太刺激了
I have to tell you, this is an absolute thrill,
我研究这个房子已经六个月了
it's been about six months I've been studying this place.
哇  这太不寻常了
Wow, that's kind of unusual!
就在这里 就是这个
Right here, this is it!
就是这里  就是你当年做采访的地方
This is it, this is the spot where you gave your interview.
- 我依稀记得 - 十年前
- I vaguely remember it. - Ten years ago!
是啊 我家里很少有工作人员
Yeah! I don't often have crews in my house.
加文在脸书上给我发了一条信息
Yeah, Gavin sent me a message on Facebook
他告诉我他找到了我的一个片段
and he told me that he found small footage of me,
所以我很想看录像
so I'm kind of interested to see the footage.
睁大你的眼睛
Keep your eyes open
很长一段时间 就是这样召唤他的
for a long time because that's how you conjure him up.
当他在那里的时候.
When he's right up there,
死亡就在眼前的那种诱惑让你无法抗拒的
the temptation is dead staring you in the face,
你要尽一切可能避开他
you do anything you can to avoid him.
门铃不错 费德曼
Nice doorbell, Feldman.
等一下 为什么我们要在这里拍摄
OK, wait a minute. Why are we doing it here
而不是在我的家里拍摄？
and not at my house with the rest of the footage?
因为我不想把摄像机从电视上拔下来
Because I don't want to unplug the camera from the TV
我不想拔下任何东西 我不想错过一切
and I don't want to unplug anything, I can't lose,
我不想离开 上次我们在你的电脑上操作的时候
I don't want to go away. The last time we did it on your computer,
带子就在我相机里头 现在拿出来了
we had the tapes in my camera, now it's in this,
你就让我好好干活吧
just let me do my thing right now, OK?
我把时间码写下来了
I got the time codes written down.
好吧 你在作什么？
OK, but what are you doing?
我得让你看一看
I just gotta show you.
我得说这对我来说是一种享受
I gotta say this is a real treat for me.
你不知道你的出镜对我的影片来说
You don't have any idea how much you validate
是多么有说服力 真的很有
what I'm working on right now, which is really great.
把它戴起来
Just feed this up through your chain.
告诉我你在这部纪录片中扮演的角色
So tell me about your role in the documentary.
哦 就是跑龙套的
Oh, it was, it was minimal.
那两个人来了 他们和我取得了联系
The two people came, they got in touch with me, they came around
我们在这里待了一个小时左右 然后他们 然后他们就离开了
and, yeah, we were here for an hour or so and then they, then they moved on.
那是我最后一次见到他们 就一次
That was the last I saw them, just once.
索菲亚 费德曼 他们是怎么和你联系上的？
Sophia, Feldman. How did they get in touch with you?
电子邮件 还是电话？ 他们给你打电话了吗 还是他们是朋友的朋友什么的？
Email, was it phone, did they call you, did somebody, friend of a friend?
我要告诉你真相 我不记得了
I'm gonna tell you the truth, I don't remember.
那是十年前的事了
It was a decade ago.
当你和我联系时 我...
When you got in touch with me, I was...
我查了我的电子邮件纪录 没有发现任何东西
I searched my email archives and didn't find anything there,
如果是电话联系的 你知道 我不存电话纪录
if it was the phone, then, you know, I don't keep phone records.
那么 偷窥狂汤姆未被编写进《古怪的马里兰》 是什么原因吗？
So, is there a reason why Peeping Tom was excluded from Weird Maryland,
很明显 伊尔切斯特隧道就在马里兰 有什么原因不写它吗？
obviously the Ilchester tunnel is in Maryland, any reason not to include it?
它只是不是什么大的故事 我个人觉得这件事
It just wasn't as strong a story, I had that kind of a vibe about it that felt more like
更像是灵异事件 而不是民间传说
what we call fakelore rather than folklore.
- 好吧  - 我有很多故事可讲
- OK. - I have a lot more stories
比我能写下的要多
than I have pages to...
那么我们来谈谈录像的事
Alright, let's talk about the footage.
我没有参与 你知道 我只是看了几集
I wasn't a part of it, you know, I just watched it for a few...
当然 作为专家
Sure, but as an expert,
如果你愿意的话 我们可以来做一次权威的学术演讲
let's get an authoritative kind of dissertation on that, if you will.
在隧道的尽头那个 呃...
That thing at the end of the tunnel with the...
- 偷窥狂汤姆 - 偷窥狂汤姆现身
- Peeping Tom. - Peeping Tom coming in,
确实是一个非常震撼的画面
it was a very striking image,
它是一个标志性的形象
it was iconic, it was an iconic image.
很可怕 那之后的事情呢？
Pretty scary. What about what happened next?
接下来要拍摄吗？
Are you rolling on this, right?
-  是的  - 好的
- Yeah. - Alright.
你想给我看什么？
What are you trying to show me?
- 请你就看 - 好的
- Just watch. - OK.
那里 你看到了吗？
There, did you see it?
好的 不 我在找什么？
OK, no. What am I looking for?
- 我要倒回去 - 好的
- I'm gonna rewind. - OK.
好吧 往左边的楼顶后面看
Alright. Look in the back on top of the building on the left.
那里 那里
There, there!
就像一只巨大的鸟 对吧？
OK, so it's like a giant bird, right?
不是 不是一只大鸟
No, it's not a giant bird.
好吧 那是什么？
OK, what is it?
你认为它是什么？
What do you think it is?
当我去换电池的时候 我发现了
When I go to change the battery and I turn out and there!
- 我到底要看什么？ 那里
- Where am I looking? - There!
就在那儿 在风管旁边
Right there, next to the air duct.
等一下
Wait a minute.
记住那个地方
But remember the spot.
我要继续了
I'm gonna go forward.
我记得 我们把它关掉了
I remember, we turned it off and...
好的 等一下 伙计
OK, wait a minute, dude...
让我理一理
This is as far as I've got.
好吧 来吧 给我看看其他的片段
OK, come on, show me the other footage.
- 好吧 - 你让我有点兴奋
- Alright, well... - You got me a little excited.
哦 我在开车 车在跑
Oh, I'm running, run, run.
- 你看到了吗？ - 没有
- Did you see that? - No!
好的 等等 等等
OK, OK, wait, wait!
放 放 好了
Play, play, alright.
准备好 准备好 就在那里
Get ready, ready, right there!
- 哦 该死 - 哦 该死
- Oh, shit! - Oh, shit!
倒带 倒带
Rewind, rewind!
准备好 别眨眼
Ready, don't blink!
- 这里 看到了吗？  - 对
- Here! There, see that? - That's right.
- 看到了吧 - 按下暂停
- Got it! - Press pause!
- 暂停 - 找到了
- Pause. - Bingo!
哦 就在这
Oh, right there.
哦 天哪 伙计 这就是他妈的眨眼人
Oh, my gosh, dude, it's fucking Blinkman!
问题是眨眼的人不是我们
Yeah, the thing is we're not the ones blinking,
是摄像机在眨眼
it's the camera that's blinking,
所以每次我切换新镜头的时候 他都在那里
so every time I'm making a new clip, he's there.
是的  等一下
Yeah, wait a minute!
每次我们打开或者关闭相机 相机都会“眨一次眼"
Every single time we turn the camera on and off and it blinks,
他越来越近了
he's almost, he's getting closer.
我不知道我参与了这样一部电影
Well, I had no idea I was being involved with a film
有点吓人 结构很好
of that kind, it was kind of scary, it was well constructed.
我们刚才看到的...你的观点是这个录像是假的
So that was, so what we just watched, your opinion is that it's fake.
不存在偷窥狂汤姆 他们在隧道里什么也没发现是吧
That there's no Peeping Tom, there's no, they didn't find anything in that tunnel.
- 是啊  - 就没了？
- Yeah. - This is all?
- 看起来 - 不够古怪是吗？
- It looked like... - All non-weird.
- 这是... - 所以没有被写进你的书里
- It's... - It didn't make your book.
我只是想弄明白
What I'm just trying to figure out is...
这两个人 这是两个人
Two human beings, alright, these are two people,
你是他们唯一的联络人
you are the only link
证明他们的存在 我打电话给你 向你解释你有多重要
to them even existing and I called you, I explained to you how important you were.
但在我看来 你并没有像我想的那么认真
It just seems to me that you're not taking it as seriously as I thought you would.
作为一个受人尊敬的作家 你的做法一点都不严谨
As an esteemed author would.
你不以为然
You're kind of brushing it off a little bit,
你住在这么远的地方
you live all the way out here,
远离任何人能找到你的地方
far away from anybody to be able to track you down.
在他们拜访你并与你探讨过这件事之后
You don't have emails conveniently right after,
你就再也不怎么回复邮件了 说什么“记不得了”
right after they came and talked to you. "I don't remember who it was.
或者什么 经常换电话运营商
I had a phone line that've been bouncing my service back and forth."
谁会这么做？ 没有人来回换运营商的
Who does that? Nobody bounces their service back and forth.
先生 在我看来这里有什么阴谋
It just sounds to me like a lot of conjecture, sir.
你不会和他们的失踪有关系吧？
You wouldn't be involved in their disappearance, well then?
- 太荒谬了 - 这就荒谬了吗？
- That's ridiculous! - Is it so ridiculous?
因为它是 它是 我不知道 那是部纪录片
Because it's, it's... I don't know, that was a documentary!
那是一部纪录片
It was a documentary.
你想说这个点子很愚蠢吗？
Were you gonna say stupid?
不 我没有说它愚蠢
No, I'm not gonna say stupid!
我能在你书里找到真真傻逼的内容
I can find stuff that's pretty stupid.
我知道你的书享誉盛名
I mean, I know it's all that year, but...
这里面写的也确实不错
But it's well put together.
我们能不拍了吗？
Look, can we cut this please?
我不录了 不录了 对不起
I'm done, I'm done! Sorry!
- 你能离开吗？ - 不
- Would you like to leave, please? - No!
米勒的城堡 我只是不明白你为什么不...
Miller's castle, I just don't understand why you're not...
我只是想让你们回答这些人是否存在
I just want you to answer whether or not these people
我可以离开这里 我可以证明这一切
exist or not. I can get out of here, I can validate this whole thing.
- 我不拍了 不拍了 - 对我来说
- I'm done, I'm done! - Just seem awfully enough
- 只是太奇怪了  - 请把这个关掉
- weird to me! - Turn this thing off, please!
所以我只不过是要找到他
So all he ought to fucking do...
回答两个该死的问题
was to answer two goddamn questions.
一 他知道索菲亚和费德曼是谁吗？
"Did he know who Sophie and Feldman were?" And:
二 他们是来拍假恐怖片的
"Were they coming to make a fake horror movie
还是来拍真正的纪实电影的
or were they're legitimate documentarian filmmakers,
去证实或者反驳一些...
looking to prove or disprove...?"
妈的
Fuck!
嗨  小伙子 你好吗？
Hi buddy, how are you doing?
你想给你爸爸一个拥抱吗？ 我很想你哦
You want to give your dad a hug? I missed you!
你呆在屋里 看到下雨了吗？
Did you stay inside, did you see the rain?
能给我一个拥抱吗？
Can I get a hug, please?
结果如何？
How did it go?
事情进行得不顺利 这是肯定的
It didn't go well, that's for sure.
你为什么用我的电脑？
Why're you using my computer?
为什么是你的电脑？
Why is it your computer?
我所有的工作内容都在上面
It's got all my work on it!
我开始用这部电脑做财务
I've started the computer to do our finances.
好吧
OK!
- 好的  - 聊聊？
- Alright! - Talk?
我们现在就在聊啊
We're talking right now.
你知道这些家伙会一直跟拍的 梅尔 那些八卦新闻就是这么出来的
You know these guys are following me around, Mel, sometimes the story comes out.
我们进去 走吧 我们谈谈
Let's go in here. Come on, we'll talk. Come on!
我们又收到了一封信
We had another letter.
- 银行来的 - 好吧
- From the bank. - OK.
- 关于我们的房子 - 好吧
- About our house. - Well, just take
- 那就取点存款吧  - 我们没有存款
- the money out of savings. - We don't have savings!
那我们在感恩节讨论的预算呢？
What about the budget that we talked about on Thanksgiving?
然后就来了你电影的事
Yeah, and then your movie happened.
我的电影 听着 这一切最终都是值得的
My movie. Listen, it's all gonna be worth it in the end,
只要这一成功 就不用再干婚礼拍摄工作了
as soon as this hits, no more wedding jobs!
这是必须要付出的代价
This is it, this is what it takes, OK?
总会有一段艰难的时期 不是吗？
There's always gonna be a tough time, alright?
想象一下 等我们赚到大钱了就可以悠闲地享受生活 看着儿子长大
Isn't it gonna be great if we can sit back and we can say, "Carter, what happened?"
卡特现在就需要钱来买新鞋子
Carter! Carter needs shoes.
这些人现在在这里 我不想再继续说下去了
These guys in here right now, I don't want to get into this anymore.
- 好吗？ 我们说完了 -我们说完了
- Alright? We're done! - Yeah! We're done.
说完了
Done!
好吧 相机是一个测试项
OK, so the camera was a test subject
它整整一个小时都盯着看没有眨眼
and stared without blinking for the entire hour,
根据传说 现在镜头能够看到偷窥狂汤姆
then according to the legend now sees Peeping Tom
每次相机眨眼 他就会离得更近
and every time it blinks, he gets closer.
换句话说 每次我们把它关掉
So, in other words, every time we turn it off
然后打开 或者做一个新的剪辑
and then on, or make a new clip.
没错 这是我们的结论 他现在在我们的相机里
Yeah. There's our thesis, he's in our camera.
我的相机 是的 你知道 一开始他出现在隧道里
My camera, and yeah, you know, first he's there in the tunnel,
当我们遇到我们的导师时他又在那里
and he was there again when we met our adviser,
当我们去看通俗作家时他又在那里
and again when we went to see the author,
每一次 他都越来越近
and in each case, he got incrementally closer.
但他仍然躲在视频小角落里 他在玩弄我们 因为这样没人会相信我们
But he's still hiding in the frame, he's making this a game, because no one will believe us,
所以我们必须把他引出来
so we have to draw him out in the open.
为什么我觉得你不像我这么兴奋？
Why I feel you're not as excited about this as I am?
费德曼 假设这一切是真的
Feldman, assuming this all really happening...
已经发生了
It's really happening!
你知道这代表什么吗？
Do you realize what this means?
这意味着我们现在在拍他
Yeah, it means we're filming him right now.
好的 关了 关了
OK, hey, turn it off, turn it off.
你怎么了？
Oh, what's your problem?
我没怎么 我还是你的导演
My problem is that I'm still directing this
直到我们弄清楚我们要做什么
and I don't want this camera on until we figure out
我不想让摄像机开着 好吗？ 快关了
what we're gonna do, OK? Turn it off!
好了 摄像机 那是什么？ 你听到了吗？
OK, so the camera's... what was that? Did you hear it?
是的
Yeah.
听起来像是每段视频的开头都有
It sounds like it's at the beginning of each new clip.
这是一个数码
It's a digital...
跟相机有关 伙计
Something to do with the camera, man,
可能是相机出问题了
I mean it might be a messed up camera...
相机的问题
Something to do with the camera.
好吧 费德曼 让我来说话 好吗？
Alright, Feldman, just let me do the talking, OK?
隧道事件之后的每个片段都有
It's on every clip after the bridge
所以我们要剪辑的有很多片段
section, so that's gonna be a lot of us going through every piece.
等一下 隧道之后的每一段都有？
Wait a second, every one after the bridge?
所以 偷窥狂汤姆一出现
So, as soon as Peeping Tom shows up,
这个声音就同时出现 你是这个意思吗？
this sound shows up at the same time, is what you're saying.
这有点疯狂 但是
This is a little crazy, but it,
有点像莫斯电码
it kind of, kind of looks like Morse code.
773为什么它只是在偷窥狂汤姆之后才出现？
Like, why would it only show up after the Peeping Tom?
我不知道 是你把它记录下来的
I don't know, you're the one that's got it documented.
我现在在问你的意见啊
I'm just asking you, as a better person.
- 纪录片摄制组而已... - 你认为
- Documentary crew... - What do you think
作为一个人你是怎么想的？为什么会这样呢？
as a human being? Why would that show up like...
我不知道 这是你想让我们看到的
I don't know, it's something that you want us to see.
我确实认为 不是你的错 也许不是你把它放进去的
I do think, it's not you, man, maybe it's not even that you put it in there,
也许是这些人在拍这段录像的时候做的
maybe it's that these guys did when they shot this footage.
不过 这有点太扯了
This is a little crazy, though.
他妈的 闭嘴
What the fuck, shut the fuck up!
什么？
What?
翻译出来是什么意思？说出来 大声说出来
What does it translate to? Say it out, say it out loud, please!
- 它说：眨眼“  - 好吧 你们能帮我个忙吗？
- It says Blink. - Alright, can you guys do me
你能看着相机吗？
a favor? Can you look at the camera?
你做的很好
I believe that you've done a good job of...
你能看着相机吗？我需要你鉴定一下
Can you look at the camera? I need you to authenticate this.
- 我需要你的帮助 - 鉴定一下？
- I need your help. - Authenticate it?
盯着镜头说
Just stare in the camera and
你刚刚找到了什么？
say what you just found for them.
我觉得它完全是伪造的
I think it's completely faked.
不管是谁拍的
Whoever shot the footage,
这些人应该已经不在了
these people that supposedly aren't around anymore,
他们显然故意把这个声音放进去了
they clearly put this sound in there.
好吧 也许是他们干的 不管是谁
OK, so maybe they did it, to so whoever...
然后那人把带子给了我 不管是谁找到了视频
So if the guy gives the tape... whoever finds the footage
然后发现了这个莫尔斯电码
and then uncovers this Morse code
或者这个每次都会出现的特定声音
or this specific sound that happens every time.
这需要做很多工作 他们必须拍摄视频
That's a lot of work, they would have had to shot the footage,
卸载 编辑 然后把它放回DV磁带上
offload it, edit it and put it back on DV tapes.
是的 好吧
Yeah, OK, well...
- 然后 然后 - 他也可以那样做
- And then, and then... - He could have done that too.
我们不知道 伙计 我们不知道这些磁带之前在哪里经历了什么
We don't know, man, we don't know where these tapes were before they came here.
他来到这里 给我们讲了一个故事
He's coming here and he tells us a story,
我们要么相信 要么不相信
then we either believe or we don't believe.
眨眼测试 第一次
Blink test, take one.
眨眼测试 第二次
Blink test, take two.
眨眼测试 第三次
Blink test, take three.
Blink test, take seven.
眨眼测试 第十三次
Blink test, take 13.
眨眼测试 第十九次
Blink test, take 19.
眨眼测试 第二十五次
Blink test, take 25.
眨眼测试 第三十二次
Blink test, take 32.
眨眼测试 第四十次
Blink test, take 40.
我不相信这个视频是真的
I do not believe that this video is authentic.
有一件事对我来说很可疑 那就是它总是出现又消失
One thing that's really suspicious to me is that it always appears
要么在屏幕之外或者在某个东西后面
and disappears, like either off-screen or behind something.
汽车经过的那个镜头
The one where the car goes past
这只是另一种常见的把戏
like that's just like another really common trick
这是常见的骗人视频里面的鬼把戏
to use to make a ghost disappear if you're hoaxing a video.
关于眨眼测试
I guess here's two points about the blink test
有两点看起来很可疑
that seemed very suspicious.
一个是
One is that
费德曼在每次他打开镜头的时候
Feldman steps in front of the camera
都站在了镜头前面
every time he turned it on.
录像按钮在相机的背面
The record button's on the back of the camera
这似乎是最方便的一种方式
and it just seems like a convenient way
来呈现那个人的轮廓
to reveal the figure.
他们好像
Like they...
我知道制作成黑白风格
I know making it black and white
是电影专业学生的风格选择
is a film student's stylistic choice,
它确实能让特效加工的痕迹
but it certainly makes it easier
变得不那么明显
to hide effects and hide manipulation.
- 我们谈谈元数据 - 好的
- Let's talk about metadata. - OK.
好吧 元数据 有显示事件进展的时间戳
Alright, the metadata. There are timestamps that show the progression of events.
这也是可以造假的
You can fake that.
你现在是在指责我捏造了这一切
You're accusing me of faking this whole thing.
听着 我不认识你 我不会那么说
Look, I don't know you, I'm not gonna say that...
不 但是你还是会收我的钱 你会的
No, but you'll take my money, you'll take my money, though.
你花钱是为了听我的意见 我现在就在给你分享我的意见啊
For my opinion, which I'm giving you.
但我们有幽灵组 不算太糟
But we got the ghost group which isn't too bad,
看来他们是你最后的救命稻草了
It seems like they were sort of your last resort.
他们是
They were,
但是他们有很大的影响力
but they have a lot of reach
如果他们相信那些灵异球体
and if they believe in orbs...
这事儿可比球体什么的更轰动 更真实、
I mean, this is certainly a lot bigger, more real than orbs.
各位 这就是我的今天
And there you have it, folks,
为你们准备的片段
the footage, the found footage I've assembled for you today.
在你们的帮助下 我们可以一起解开这个谜
With your help, we can figure out the mystery, together,
因此你们在这个过程中
and that's why it's very, very crucial
紧跟我的步伐至关重要
you know, that you follow me on this quest.
有问题吗？
Any questions?
没有问题 我能指望你们的支持吗？请说 女士
No questions! Can I count on your support? Yes, ma'am.
你不知道他们有没有请人伪造
You don't know that they didn't have somebody to do this,
你不知道这些是不是真的 你不知道他们在做什么
you don't know if any of this is real, you don't know what they do...
你说的对 女士 这就是我们今晚来这里的原因
You're right, ma'am, and that's why we're here this evening,
因为如果我知道这是真的
because if I knew if it was real,
那我就不需要你们了 伙计们
then I wouldn't need you, folks.
如果他在隧道的尽头
If he's at the end of the tunnel
而那些是铁路枕木
and those are railroad ties,
他必须有六英尺宽
he'd have to be about six feet wide.
六英尺宽
Six feet wide.
视频里没有人
There's nobody in that video
你可以找到并交谈的吗？
that you could find in public records to speak with?
我确实找到了马特·莱克
I did find this Matt Lake,
他是《古怪的马里兰》的作者
he's an author of a book called Weird Maryland,
如果你想的话可以去找他 但我不建议
which you can pick up if you want to, I mean I don't recommend it.
我很难相信像我这样在你们面前做展示的人
I find it very hard to believe that people who come up in front of your group
竟会受到这样的盘问
constantly get grilled like this,
我还以为你们都很相信这类事情呢
it seems to me that everybody be in, everybody be into it.
我想说的是 这足以让我们
I'd say this would be enough to warrant
对这个实验进行调差和再创造
an investigation and a recreation of the experiment.
超自然群体需要的不仅仅是视觉证据
Paranormal groups need more than just a piece of visual evidence
从方法论上来说
to be able to methodologically
去量化和限定一个事件
quantify and qualify an event.
我们需要音频 我们需要...
We would need audio, we would need...
先生 先生 抛开那些花言巧语 我明白你的意思
Sir, sir, all the fancy words aside, I get what you're saying.
我要你做的就是 要么相信 要么不相信
All I'm asking you to do, is either believe it or you don't
要么去调查 要么不去
and you want to go investigate it or you don't.
我想知道你都吃些什么药？
I'd like to know what kind of medications that you take?
我 女士 我认为这太粗鲁了
I, ma'am, I think that that's extremely rude
我不认为这和那有任何关系
and I don't think that has any bearing on that.
我想问你在服用什么药物来问这些问题？
I'd like to ask you what medications you're on to ask such questions?
要是你拍一部关于血腥玛丽的电影时
When you get a film on Bloody Mary,
也许我们会考虑一下
maybe we'll think about it,
但这是无稽之谈 我们不想和它扯上任何关系
but this is a crock and we want nothing to do with it.
你所说的是追踪一个鬼魂 而我们并不打算加入你
And that's inspired ghost tracking. Now, we're not going out to investigate with you.
我很确定你所谓的这个鬼魂追踪...
I'm pretty sure that inspired ghost tracking...
这不会是你们最后一次听说我
This is not gonna be the last time that you hear about me.
这是出口门吗？
Is this the exit door?
没有球 但谢谢你们 我很感激
No orbs out there, but thank you very much, I appreciate it.
我相信你们以后会收到我的消息的
I'm sure that you'll be hearing from me in the future and yeah...
请把相机关掉
Turn off the camera, please!
我现在不想拍了
I don't want to deal with it right now.
他就在那儿
And there he fucking is.
现在 我们的问题是 每当我们移动相机的时候
Now, our problem is that any time that we moved the camera,
不管我们是在移动相机 还是在车里或走路的时候
whether we were just moving the camera or we were in a car or walking,
他都能在屏幕上跳来跳去 所以
he was able to flip in and out of the screen, so,
我们无法追踪他
we couldn't keep track of him,
但是如果我把相机留在它原来的位置
but if I leave the camera where it is,
他就被困住了 我把它弄到我想要他呆的地方了
then he's stuck and I got it where I fucking want him!
现在 我们真正需要的是 我们需要得到结果
Now, what we really need to get right now, is we need to get the ending.
现在 对我来说 最符合逻辑的事情是
Now, the most logical thing for me to think of is, you know,
我要用这个特写镜头来揭示惊天大秘密
it's the closeups as a grand reveal.
你为什么用便携式摄像机拍我？
Why are you filming me with the Handycam?
你怕我的相机
You're afraid of my camera.
大导演 这一开始是你的主意
Well, that figures, I mean directors, you always had this vision and you think
你也考虑过要如何去做,但是你对镜头记录下的一切,一点都拿不准
what you want to do with it, but behind the camera, you have no fucking idea!
他走得越来越近 他不能再靠近了
He keeps on getting closer and that's where he needs to stay.
他在我的相机上
He's on my camera!
哦 该死
Oh, shit!
嘿  看
Hey, well, look...
你拿着这些日记干什么？
What are you up to with all these journals here?
等一下
Wait a minute.
这是某种
That's some kind of
好的 鬼眨眼 视频日记什么的 随便吧
OK, Butterfly Kisses, video diary, whatever, right.
我并不想指责费德曼做了什么
So, I don't really want to accuse Feldman of doing anything
我也没有说他在撒谎 好吗？
and I'm not even saying that he's lying, OK?
我真的很尊敬他
I really do respect him.
但是在看了他的日记之后
But after reading his diary a little while ago,
他有所有的图表
and him having the diagrams of everything,
我只是想把这些记录下来留给子孙后代
I just want to record this for posterity and just
确保每个人都知道我对整个事件有疑问 好吗？
make sure that everyone knows that I have my doubts about this entire project, OK?
现在 我对一切都心存疑虑
Right now, I have doubts about everything.
老实说 还有比这更糟的吗？
Honestly, what could be worse?
知道偷窥狂汤姆随时会来抓我
Knowing that Peeping Tom could come and get me at any moment
或者只是因为这整件事被大家嘲笑
or just being humiliated by the entire thing,
费德曼以后可以在学生电影节上展示这个
knowing that Feldman can show this at the student film festival
而我什么都不是
and I look like a fucking ass!
我只能听天由命了 希望那家伙不是在跟我开玩笑
I'm just gonna have to roll with it and hope the fella isn't fucking with me,
因为我是真的开始相信了
like I'm really, really starting to believe.
首先 你给了我录像
First off, you gave us the footage and we wanted to see
我们想看看你删掉的东西
all of those things that you cut out.
你能告诉我们《死去朋友的肖像》是什么吗？
Can you please tell us, can you tell us what Portraits of Dead Friends was?
我们最终赢得了学生电影节 最佳故事片奖
We actually ended up winning our student film festival, Best Feature Award for it.
两位电影制作人 索菲亚和费德曼拍摄过
The same two filmmakers, Sophia and Feldman, made a movie
另一部叫《死去朋友的肖像》
called Portraits of Dead Friends in which they wanted to make
他们想要制作一部关于已逝之人的电影
a film about people who were deceased,
但是他们不想做些平凡的东西
but they didn't want to do the usual kind of, you know:
"他是一个很棒的人 他出生在这样那样的地方"
"He was a wonderful person and he was born in such and such place."
所以 他们转而去看那个人的讣告旁边的照片
So instead, they went to the photograph that appeared with the person's obituary.
那和偷窥狂汤姆无关
Well, A. That has nothing to do with Peeping Tom.
这和偷窥狂汤姆有关
It has everything to do with Peeping Tom!
别谈这个话题 天哪
I didn't want you to bring that on, oh my gosh!
我很高兴你笑了
I'm glad you laughed at it.
- 我是说 我不擅长这个  - 你看起来还行
- I mean, I'm not good about it. - You seem pretty OK with it.
好吧 听着 那个姑娘的妹妹不想谈论她
Ok, look, the girl's sister didn't want to talk about her.
这是一个非常好的故事 我们也找到了一个非常棒的演员 这很重要
It was a really good story, so we got a freaking actor in there, big deal.
作为纪录片制片人
As documentary filmmakers,
他们愿意让一个演员扮演一个人
they were willing to have an actor
并因此获奖
play a person and accept award for it.
当然
Sure.
你认为《肖像》足够了吗？
Do you think Portraits was enough...
- 不加入那个故事的元素？ - 你什么意思
- without that story? - What do you mean "Do you think
你觉得画肖像就够了吗 是什么意思？
Portraits was enough without that story"?
我们有五个故事 你在说什么故事？
There's five stories, what story?
你知道我在说什么
You know what story I'm talking about.
黛安娜的吗？
Diana's?
就是我们...
The one that we, you know...
我捉摸不透费德曼这个人 他有一点小情绪
I'm not sure about Feldman, he's got a bit of an attitude,
因为他想当导演 他想当老大
because he wants to be the director, he wants to be the top dog.
也许他有一些怨恨的情绪
Maybe there was some resentment going on there.
我找到了一段费德曼
I found a clip where Feldman
说他没有获奖的片段 说全都是索菲亚一人的荣誉
is saying that he did not win an award, that it was just Sophia.
你拿你的奖状做了什么？
What did you do with your award?
我没有得到奖
I didn't get one.
等等 你什么意思 你没有得到？
Wait, what do you mean, you didn't get one?
我是说 沃尔夫博士给你了 而且上面只有你的名字
I mean, Dr. Wolfe only gave it to you, and it only has your name on it!
你是当真的吗？
Are you serious?
费德曼有轻微的心理不平衡
Feldman turns out to have his own mildly unscrupulous streak,
因为他开始建议
because he starts to suggest,
我们可以做一些事情
there are things we could do
如果我们得不到温控希望得到的形象
if we don't get the image that we're hoping to get.
我们可以做一些事情
There's other things.
比如加特效之类的？
Like what, like visual effects, kind of thing?
就像这样
Something like that.
所以我们至少有三种可能
So we have then at least three possibilities here.
有可能整件事都是真的
We have the possibility that this whole thing is real,
他们拍到了偷窥狂汤姆的画面
that they caught the image of Peeping Tom.
我们有可能他们两个聚在一起
We have the possibility of two of them got together,
把这个看似可信的恶作剧拍成作品
to put together this largely plausible hoax
也有可能他们两个其中一人恶搞了另一个人的作品
and we have the possibility that one of them put together a hoax on the other one.
至少这三种可能性
At least those three possibilities.
我得说
I need to say...
我最开始对他的印象是 他像一个在幕后默默无闻的人
I guess my initial prejudice was the slacker who was kind of quiet in the background,
而且我认为他就是个未知因素 后来才发现原来他才是一切的主谋
was the X-factor, yeah, he was the instigator of the fiction
鬼眨眼 视频日记一
Butterfly Kisses, video diary one.
回想起来 我觉得索菲亚似乎更像是越界了
On reflection, it seems much more to me as though Sophia, she maybe crossed the line.
你知道 当你在一个故事上投入了大量时间 而最后期限即将到来时
You know, when you've invested a lot of time in a story and the deadline's coming up,
诱惑就来了 我怎样才能让这个故事变得警察呢？
the temptation is, yeah, how do I make this a good story?
不幸的是 我不能证明偷窥狂汤姆只是一个演员和一顶帽子而已
Unfortunately I can't prove that Peeping Tom wasn't anything more than just an actor and a hat.
这很糟糕 因为我不知道接下来要做什么
Which is kind of sucks, because I don't know what I'm gonna do from here.
我想 我需要一个新的角度
I guess, I'm just gonna need a new angle.
从那以后的一切
And then, everything from that that point onwards
都是二人协作的产物
was a collaboration in this fiction.
这与那个故事无关
It wasn't relevant to the story.
那他们站在老伊斯特隧道的场景呢
What about the scene where they're standing in the old Ilchester Tunnel,
费德曼说 如果老实拍摄达不到目的的话
and Feldman is saying if this doesn't work with the camera looking through the tunnel,
我们可以做一个特效
we could do a special effect.
我认为他们只是绝望而已
I mean that's, I think that's desperate times and spitballing,
你知道 这只是说说而已 都是信口开河
you know, it's just talk, it's all loose talk.
当一个人想要 你知道
When someone wants, you know,
仅仅是说出他们的真相
just to speak their truth and to bring it out
并把它展示给其他人
to other people and to kind of have that position
一次来获得某种领导地位 名声和其他一切
of leadership and fame and everything else,
他们会专门选择一些特定的事情来支持自己的行为
they will cherry-pick certain things that support what they're doing.
大脑并不是有意识地去挑选或无视某些真相
Your brain is not consciously cherry-picking,
这更多是一种无意识的事情
it is more of an unconscious thing.
对于某人来说
So, it's very easy for someone,
当他们开始形成
as they're starting to get in
一种强迫性的行为或一种错觉
to, you know, kind of an obsessive behavior or a delusion is starting to be created
他们此时如果看待所谓的证据以及那些重要信息
where the look at a piece of evidence and the things that highlight for them,
他们就会无意识地放大 而对于那些不重要的信息
they zoom and sink into the brain immediately and then the things that don't,
大脑会自动地把它们遗忘
the brain automatically kind of just
把他们遗忘 就像它们根本不存在一样
sections them off like they don't even exist.
加文·约克决定把这些材料展现出来
Gavin York's decision to take that material out
这个行为表明他
suggests a manipulative,
有很强的操纵欲
a very strong manipulative intent on his part.
如果你手头上有这些素材
If you're working with all these elements, you can,
从新闻的角度来说 你可以构造
journalistically speaking, you can construct the...
你可以用任何你选择的素材来讲述这个故事
You run the story out of whatever footage you choose to put in there.
如果他把这些场景删除
If he took these scenes out,
他肯定有一个特别的理由
then he had a particular reason for doing it.
至于为什么他允许你将片段放回去
Why he's allowing you to put them back in
或者说利用它们 这背后的原因很有趣
or to utilize them in some way, It's interesting.
我是说 有 有 能再重复一遍吗？
I mean, there's, there's... Pardon?
- 他签署了一份声明 - 是的
- He signed a release. - Yeah.
他授权他人使用
He authorized the use of the footage
这部纪录片中的镜头
in this documentary.
有人说也许是
There, there are people who suggested that
也许加文自己也拍了这些东西
perhaps Gavin shot this himself.
你觉得那是
Do you feel that's...
我认为那不是真的
I don't think that's true.
他什么时候会这么做呢？
Simply because, when would he have done it?
我妈妈在地下室找到了磁带
I mean, my mom found the tapes in the basement, so...
你为什么有松下DVX100
Why do you own a Panasonic DVX100?
- 费德曼就是用这台相机拍的纪录片 - 好吧
- That's the camera that Feldman filmed the documentary on. - OK.
他们说他经常去旅行
They say he goes away on a lot of trips.
是的 他去婚礼举办地
Yeah, he goes where the weddings are.
钱是否全部匹配？
Does the money all match up?
基本上是
Usually!
停
Stop!
我要磁带
I want the tapes!
你的脸怎么了？
What happened to your face?
- 很痒 - 你有事吗？
- It itched. - Are you on something?
不  睫毛会勾到痒痒的地方
No, I thought the lashes would tick over the itch.
还有相机
And the camera,
我把它锁在地下室了
I locked it in the basement.
我把电池扔了
I threw away the battery!
当我从睡梦中醒来 它又回来了
And when I woke up from sleeping, it was back.
它在拍我 他在拍我
It was taping me, he was taping me.
你以为是我按下了这个快门键吗？
Do you think it was me that pressed record for this?
不 他知道你要来 所以我才知道你要来
No, he knew you were coming, that's how I knew you were coming.
我要在他达到目的之前让这一切结束
I'm gonna get the ending that he aimed for before he does,
这一切都取决于你 磁带给你了
but then it's all on you, you got the tapes.
但我会把所有的镜头都拍下来 你要照你说的完成这部电影
But I'm gonna get all the footage, you finish this movie like you said you would!
还记得吗？
Remember?
那之后他就会去找你了
And then he's coming after you.
你是下一个
You're next.
但你会赢得另一个奖项
But you'll win another award!
这是我的新网站
This is my new delivery system
www.butterflykissesmovie.com.
- 嗨 你好 - 嗨 我在找乔安妮·蒂尔曼小姐
- Hello! - Hi there, I'm looking for Miss Joanne Tillman?
她现在不在 要我帮你留言吗？
She's not available right now, may I take a message?
是的 我是加文·约克
Yeah, this is Gavin York calling,
这实际上是我三天打的第七次电话了
this is actually the seventh time that I've called in the past three days.
周五 当计时器从
On Friday, when the timer runs down,
午夜到凌晨一点的时候
from midnight to 1 a.m.,
届时 世界各地的观众将能够
viewers around the world will be able to watch footage,
观看这些片段
the found footage,
并且能够对其进行评论
and be able to make their own assessment of it.
我们要把它公之于众 所以
We're gonna get it out on the world, so...
24小时后会发生什么？
What's gonna happen after the 24 hours?
网站会被关闭 你再也看不到它了
The website's gonna be shut down, you're not gonna be able to see it anymore.
那你预计会发生什么？
What do you expect to happen then?
从那以后电话会一直响个不停
The phone does never stop ringing after that.
所以你会把它卖给出价更高的人？
So you'll sell it to the highest bidder?
或者一个 你知道的 适度的 一个 是的
Or one, just, you know, moderate. One, so yeah, yeah.
我不是要装模作样
I'm not trying to be a jerk,
我只是想知道怎样和蒂尔曼小姐说上话
I just want to find out how I can speak with
告诉她一些关于我周五
Miss Tillman and give her some information about
要参加的当地社区活动的消息
a local community event that I've got going on on Friday.
喂
Hello...
Hello!
有多少家报纸
How many, how many newspapers in...
所有的
All of them.
- 所有的？ - 所有的
- Already all? - All of them.
你还没明白吗？
And you see how it is?
你亲耳听到的
You heard it for yourself,
他们才不在乎呢 挂断 挂断
they don't give a shit! Hang up, hang up!
我是说 除非你
I mean, unless you...
你认识什么人吗？
Do you know somebody?
你知道 我们不能介入
You know, we can't get involved.
我们必须待在相机的这一边
We have to stay on this side of the camera.
随你便 爱站在镜头的那边就站吧  伙计
Stay on that side of the camera if you want to, man.
我不知道你们为什么要坐在这里拍我 不参与进来
I mean, I don't know why you guys want to sit here and film me, and not get involved,
因为你们也是在浪费时间
because you're just wasting your time too.
这部电影没有任何结局
There's no ending to this movie whatsoever.
你的电影有很棒的结局
You get an awesome ending for your movie,
我的电影也有很棒的结局
I get an awesome ending for my movie.
没人说谎 没人说假话 对吧？
Nobody's lying, nobody's saying anything fake, alright?
我只需要一个电话号码和一个名字
All I'm asking for is one telephone number and a name.
我们可以去找那个人 我们可以吧整个故事讲出来
And that we can go, and we can speak to that person and we can put this whole story out there.
我不认为
I don't think...
这是作弊
it's cheating
为了巨大的回报在所难免
if it's for the great reward.
这里是华盛顿101 我是迈克·琼斯
It's DC 101, I'm Mike Jones and
在我们的演播室里
in studio today I've been talking about
关于《鬼眨眼》片段的话题已经进行了一周了
this found footage all week, Butterfly Kisses.
加文·约克 发现了这段录像的人
Gavin York, the guy that discovered this footage,
你们可以自己去看 如果你们还没有看的话
and you could see it for yourself, if you haven't yet,
直到今晚午夜 在butterflykissesmovie.com上可以看到
until midnight tonight at butterflykissesmovie.com.
加文·约克 你好吗？兄弟
Gavin York, how you doing, brother?
我很好 谢谢
I'm doing great, thanks for...
我只是不明白
I just don't understand the deal
这家伙怎么了 伙计
with this guy, man,
你为什么要拍他 这对你有什么好处？
why are you filming him, what's in it for you with this?
这应该是
It's supposed to be
一个非常棒的角色研究 事实证明确实如此
a really fantastic, fascinated character study. And then it is!
没有人愿意来
Nobody wants to come to...
因为之前已经做过很多次了
Because this has been done a thousand times before.
我们认为这是一个骗局
And we think it's a scam.
不只是我 大家都是
I'm not the only one, it's everyone!
我知道 但这是我现在面临的问题
I know, but that's the problem that I've got right now,
我已经拍了好几个小时的录像
I've got hours and hours of footage that we've shot,
但是我们没有给这部纪录片一个结局
but we don't have an ending to this documentary.
你给了我这个机会
And you give me this opportunity to...
- 这是...   - 这太棒了
- This is the... - This is amazing!
没关系 我支持你
It's alright, I got your back.
- 只是不要...  - 好的
- Just don't... - Alright.
好的 我们看看人们怎么说 这是华盛顿101号 请8669 1号观众
Alright, well, we'll see what the people have to say, it's 8669 1 DC 101.
嗨 DC101
Hi, DC 101!
你真的认为有人
Yeah, you actually think there's
会傻到相信这个鬼东西吗？
anyone stupid enough to fall for that?
视频质量糟透了 都是假的
The video quality sucks, it's all fake.
加文 你有什么要说的吗？
Gavin, do you have anything to say?
这是2004年要解决的事了
Well, I mean, this would be something in 2004 to address with them!
不 伙计 可是现在不是2004年啊 你现在才做这些蠢事
No man, you totally didn't do this in 2004, you did this just now.
2004年我什么都没做没错 我现在才将影片汇集好
I didn't do anything in 2004, I just assembled it now.
我不想从任何事情中获利
I'm not trying to profit off anything.
你找过他们吗？
Have you looked for them?
把它带到警察局去...
Take it to the police...
你只要检查一下 那是假的
...just check it out, that's bogus.
加文 怀疑论无处不在
Gavin, skepticism is just everywhere.
- 是的 网络上有很多仇恨言论 - 一点点 一点点
- Yes, a lot of hatred out there. - A little bit, a little bit.
别浪费时间了 去探索一下你真正可能擅长的事情吧
Hang it up and find something else that you might be good at.
改变自己 因为你这是想从别人的死亡中获利
Change yourself, because you're trying to profit off of somebody's death.
你该不是真的认为人们会相信吧
You think that people are gonna fall for this.
这是个骗局
Showing a hoax it's...
我看那些垃圾的每一分每一秒都...
The second I spent watching that piece of...
你看起来像个瘾君子
You seem like a stoner...
无论哪个项目...
...whichever project...
这是错的 诅咒
...wrong about this, cursed...
不是真的
...not real.
你好 我DC101 你是谁？
Hello, DC 101, who's this?
史丹利
Stanley.
史丹利 你要对加文说什么？
Stan, what you gotta say to Gavin?
好吧 我告诉你
Alright, I'll tell you what.
我给他五分钟的时间
I'll give him five minutes
我想我找到一个人了
and I think I've got a guy,
我们可以让我的制作人打电话
we can get my producer to call.
会好起来的 看看会发生什么
It'll be good. See what happens.
对他有好处还是？
Good for him or?
这对我们都有好处
It'll be good for us.
加文 听着 我知道人们一直在喷你
Gavin, listen, I know people have been blasting you.
我想...
I want to...
这是我们一直在等的电话.
This is the call that we've been waiting for,
让我把他接过来
let me bring him on here.
- 你好 来电者 - 你好
- Hello, caller! - Yes.
嗨 让我给你介绍一下
Hi, let me introduce you.
加文 这是埃德·桑切斯 旧片重制的王牌制作人
Gavin, this is Ed Sanchez, the king of the found footage,
女巫布莱尔项目的导演
the director of the Blair Witch Project
他打电话来谈论你的电影 鬼眨眼
who is calling to talk about your movie Butterfly Kisses!
艾德 你好吗 兄弟？
Ed, how you doing, brother?
我很好 伙计 最近怎么样？
I'm doing well, man how's it going?
- 很好  - 下午好 我是你的大粉丝
- Good. - Good afternoon! Big, big fan!
我看过录像
I've seen the footage.
在我看来它并不完全是真的
You know, it doesn't look completely genuine to me.
我认为这其中涉及到一些表演 一些效果
You know, I think there's some acting involved, there's some effects involved,
我认为有点令人不安的是
and I think that it's kind of disturbing that he feels that
他觉得推广这段视频的唯一方法就是假装它是真实的
the only way to market this footage is to pretend it's real.
我只是不得不说出来 你知道吗？
So, you know, I just kind of had to speak out about it, you know?
我理解加文的想法 但是 你知道
I understand where Gavin's coming from,
他想要 你知道 他在努力
but, you know, he's trying to, you know,
进入这个行业 他想拍这部电影
get in the business, he's trying to make this film,
以前也有过这种事情 这是
but it's just been done before, it's a...
你这样做事为了在好莱坞开始你的职业生涯？
Did you do this to start your career in Hollywood?
这是你踢开那扇门的方式吗？
Is this your way of maybe kicking that door open?
我从12岁左右就开始拍电影了
I've been a filmmaker since I was about 12 years old.
对 这就是为什么每个人都说
Right, that's why everyone's saying
这不是真正的电影
that this is not footage that is legitimate,
这是你在电脑上做出来的
that you created this on your computer.
我完全理解这一点
I completely understand that.
你拍过真正的电影
And you've made this your film.
你是个专业人士
You're a professional.
我想问你 你能只用几个项目
Could you have made this on a computer at home
就在家里的电脑上做出来这东西吗？
with just a few projects?
至少对我来说 作为一名电影制作人
At least for me, as a filmmaker,
你可以看出有些东西
you can tell that there's some stuff
显然是被刻意加进去的
that is obviously, you know, manipulated.
有一些瞬间
There's like these moments of...
恰好在摄像机开着的时候 捕捉到一些场景
Where just the camera happens to be on, to capture a moment.
所有的旧片重制都是这么开始的
That's like a big thing of found footage is like.
当一些疯狂的事情发生的时候 摄像机正好开着
The camera happens to be on while something crazy's happening,
你知道 你只是在生活中没有那种运气
you know, you just don't have that kind of luck in life, you know.
这整个故事都是在一个鞋盒里找到的
The whole legend is that the footage is found in a shoebox
有一些镜头专门拍摄了发现鞋盒的过程
and the footage carefully shows like oh, here's this shoebox
我们在这里找到的这个鞋盒 给摄像机看一下
that we found it in here, I'll show it in front of the camera,
就像他们在刻意设置了鞋盒场景一样
which is like something that they're setting up the shoebox, you know.
对我来说 这些都是
To me those are kind of, you know,
你正在戏剧性地摆设的迹象
signs that you're setting something up dramatically.
在电影里你会这样做
In a movie you do that, you know.
在我们的电影开始轰动之后
You know, after the initial buzz of our movie,
我们从来没有假装那是真的
we never pretended that it was real.
我只是不相信他说的是真的
I just have a problem with him thinking that it's for real.
也许我觉得是他有问题
You know, maybe I think he has a problem.
艾德 如果这件事被发现
Ed, what are gonna be the consequences if this does come out
是加文编造的会有什么后果？
and it's found out that Gavin made this up?
你这样做实际上
You're just kind of really
是在破坏你的声誉
destroying your reputation with this,
因为最终会有人站出来
because eventually somebody's going to come out,
证明这不是真的
some proof is gonna come out that this is not real,
你知道 人们会问你在想什么？
and, you know, people are gonna ask what were you thinking?
我现在想问的也是 他在想什么？
And I'm kind of asking that right now, what is he thinking?
坦白点说 你知道我的意思
You know, just fess up, you know what I mean or...
我尽量诚实的告诉你
I'm being about as honest as I can be about this.
好吧 随你怎么说
Alright, well, you say so.
感谢今天的嘉宾加文·约克 大家去看看他的网站吧
Well, Gavin York, check out the movie butterflykissesmovie.com,
将开演到今天午夜 谢谢
it's on until midnight tonight, thank you!
DC 101!
梅尔？
Mel?
嘿
Hey!
没关系的
It's alright!
她妈妈开了个账户
Her mom set up an account.
为卡特开的
For Carter and
他们都投入了资金
they were putting money into it.
但我把所有的钱都花在了电影上
And I took all the money and I spent it on the movie.
她是怎么知道的？
How did she find out?
她想去取一笔钱
She wanted to go and take out a sum.
今天上午当局报告
Authorities report that the strange death
一名当地男子的离奇死亡
of a local man leaves more questions
给人民留下了不少疑惑
than answers this morning.
朋友们说 电影专业的学生
Friends say that Feldman,
费德曼最近行为怪异
a film student, had been acting strangely.
是啊 他一直在拍这部电影
Yeah, he's been making this movie with this...
尸体躺在地上 摔得粉碎
The body was lying on floor, smashed to pieces.
费德曼的尸体是在厨房水槽下面的橱柜里找到的
Feldman's body had been found in the cabinet, under the kitchen sink.
这个生物来了
This creature is coming and...
目前 当局正在等待尸检报告
At this time, authorities await results of an autopsy.
希望我们今晚能和他拍一些镜头
Hopefully we have a record with him this evening and, you know,
弄清楚他去了哪里 如果他给我们打电话就最好 很明显
figure out where he's been, if he's giving us a call, obviously we're,
我们是来这里拍摄的 我们只是在为子孙后代
you know, we're showing up there to shoot, we're just filming this for posterity
- 拍摄这个的  - 是的
- at this point. - Yeah.
说实话 我不认为我们会在这方面花太多时间
I don't really think we're gonna use much about this, to be honest.
当然 我同意
Sure, I agree!
你要我继续讲下去 这样我们就
You want me to keep rolling on this so that we have...
随便做些什么吧
Just whatever you do.
我没剩多少电池了
I don't have a lot of battery left.
如果你是对的 好吧
If you're right about it. Alright!
加文
Gavin!
嘿 加文
Hey, Gavin!
加文
Gavin!
我先不录了
I'm gonna stop recording for a second.
不 不 继续
No, no, just keep it rolling.
不 我们在这里录什么？
No, what are we recording here?
这什么都不是 我不...
We're not doing anything, I don't...
去跟他谈谈 伙计 这有点
Go talk to him or something, man, this is getting...
我甚至不知道该对他说什么
I don't even know what to say to him!
我不知道 艾瑞克 你是导演
I don't know, Erik, you're the director!
加文
Gavin!
听着 伙计 如果你不跟我们说话 我们帮不了你
Look, buddy, we can't help you if you don't talk to us.
这不是...
It's not...
不只是他在靠近你
Just when he gets closer to you...
更重要的是你在靠近他
It's when you get closer to him...
等等 你在说什么？
Wait, what are you talking about?
鬼眨眼
Butterfly kisses!
我们得帮帮他 说真的
We need to help this guy, seriously.
我们打电话给他老婆
We call, we call his wife!
我们没有她的电话号码 她换了电话号码 我不知道她的新号码是多少
We don't have her number. She changed her number. I don't know what her new number is.
她的岳母呢？ 不知道她的名字
What about his, what about his mom-in-law? Whatever her name was.
我没有她的电话号码
I never had her number.
它通过阿米莉亚
It worked through Amelia,
卖掉房子的
and the house is sold,
所以我不知道如何找到她
so I don't even know how to find her.
我不知道 我是说 我不是...
I don't know, I mean, I'm not...
我们应该拍一部关于他的电影
We're supposed to make it a movie about him,
我说不好这是不是我们的职责 但是我们毕竟不是他的家人
and I don't know how much, if this is our responsibility, we're not, not his family.
现在是我们的责任了...
It is our responsibility now, we've...
我们和他一起到今天这个地步的
We've taken him this far,
我们在一些事情上
we've kind of screwed him over
耍了他
on a couple things!
我们没有骗过他 肯尼
We haven't screwed him over, Kenny!
但是DC101那件事是下了套的
But, DC 101 was total set up.
DC101 他同意了
DC 101 who's not a total set up, he agreed to it.
他不知道你要叫艾德·桑切斯给他打电话
He didn't know you were gonna have Ed Sanchez call him. Come on!
我没有让他在直播中失败
I did not put him on the air to fail,
我们给了他选择
we gave him that option.
听着 这是互斥互利的 我们 我们...
Look, it was mutually exclusive, mutually beneficial. We, we...
我们需要一个电影的结尾 他需要一个公共论坛来发言
We needed an end to the movie, and he needed a public forum through which to speak.
我们同意的
We agreed on this.
这怎么 这怎么是我的错？
How is that, how is that my fault?
- 你们这些人都说 - 为了你的电影你毁了他的生活
- You guys, all said... - You ruin his life for your movie,
这么说如何？
how about that?
从什么时候开始我的电影
At what point did this become my movie
毁了别人的生活？
and this became I ruin somebody's life?
伙计 你逼得他继续的
Man, you just keep pushing him. You keep...
那为什么你们这些家伙
Why do you guys, why do you guys keep showing up
为什么你们一直带着装备出现在镜头前 为什么要一直参与其中呢？
with the gear and shooting, what we're doing then?
如果你道德感真有这么强
If you're so, if you have such moral issues with it,
你为什么他妈的在这里？
why are you fucking here?
- 那是谁？  - 什么？
- Who's that? - What?
有人跑过铁轨
Somebody's running across the tracks.
- 来吧 伙计们 - 该死
- Come on, guys. - Shit!
相机在哪里？他拿了相机吗？
Where is the camera? Did he take the camera?
伙计们 慢点
Guys, slow down.
- 他真的去那儿吗？ -我才不进去
- Did he seriously go in there? - I'm not going in there.
伙计们 相机电池快没电了
Guys! The camera battery is getting low!
我们必须在这里做出决定
We have to make a decision here.
加文
Gavin!
埃里克 照相机快关机了
The camera is about to die, Erik!
我们在做什么？
What are we doing?
- 那是什么？ - 什么？
- What is that? - What?
- 那他妈的是谁？  - 加文
- Who the fuck is that? - Gavin!
- 你看见了吗？  - 就在那儿
- Did you see? - It's right there.
- 你看到什么了吗？ - 我什么都没看见
- Did you see anything? - I don't see anything!
就在他妈的隧道的尽头 那他妈的是什么？
It's right in fucking the end of the tunnel! What the fuck is...?
费德曼死的那天晚上寄来的
Feldman sent this the night that he died.
如你所见 他详细说明了他所谓的最终计划
As you can see, he details out what he called the final plan.
最后 他只能眨三次眼了 所以他把相机对着镜子
At the end, he only had three blinks left, so he set the camera up
这样他就能看到两边的情况 身前身后都可以
into a mirror, so he covered both sides, the front and the back of himself.
他在镜子前蹲下来
He crouched down in front of the mirror
准备好锤子 这样在他最后的一眨眼功夫
and had this hammer ready, so that on his final blink
他就可以阻止 他可以阻止他找到他 他至少是这么认为的
he could stop, he could stop him from getting him, so he thought...
费德曼死了之后 他的父母让我帮他收拾他的所有东西
Feldman's parents let me go over and go through everything when
因为毕竟最后是我们俩一起在弄这个项目
Feldman had passed, because we were working on the project together.
我拿到了摄像机里最后的带子
I was able to get this tape which was in the camera, up until the end.
正如所看到的那样 这个带子被打碎了 而且磁带还没有卷起来
As you can see, it's all cracked up and the tape was unspooled,
但我还是把它修好了
but I was actually able to put it back together.
花了几天时间
It took a few days,
但我做到了
but I did it.
唯一能播放的是最后一段
The only thing that would play, was the last clip,
没关系 因为费德曼很聪明
and that's OK, because Feldman was smart.
他还准备了这个
He also had this.
啊
Ah!
好的 安迪 鉴于摄像机已经开拍了
Alright, so Andy, for the benefit of the camera, can you please,
你能告诉我你在邮件里给我发了什么吗？
can you please tell me what you sent me in the email?
我发现的是
Well, what I found was,
你可以看到偷窥狂汤姆突然起身
if you look when Peeping Tom is jumping up,
抓住了费德曼
like jumping up to grab Feldman...
如果你看他的眼睛 实际上他的眼睛里有一个图像
If you look in his eye, there's actually an image in his eye.
起初 我以为这是伊尔切斯特隧道的画面
At first, I thought it was the shot of the, like the Ilchester tunnel,
我以为这是他之前出现在镜头里的
like I thought it was like a frame grab from the video
画面的粘贴
where he appeared, but
但实际上不是的 正好相反
I actually think it's the other way around,
这其实是偷窥狂汤姆视角
like it's what Peeping Tom saw
当偷窥狂汤姆出现的时候
when Peeping Tom appeared
他往隧道另一头看去
so he's looking through the tunnel
你可以看到摄像机发出的光
and... you see the lights from that camera
再往外看就和火车桥一样
and beyond that is like the train bridge.
好的 这是他的视角
OK, so this, this is his POV
看到了克兰和费德曼在夜间拍摄他...
of Crane and Feldman filming him the night...
这是偷窥狂汤姆的视角 没错
It's Peeping Tom's point of view, yeah.
哇 啊...
Wow, ah...
这是它原本的声音
So this is what it sounds like by itself.
你不一定能看出
You wouldn't necessarily be able to tell
这是莫斯电码
that that's Morse code,
但你可以从他的波幅看出
but you can see that it looks
这就是莫斯电码
a hell of a lot like it.
所以 上次我们和加文一起工作的时候
So, we, last time we were working with Gavin,
有一些关于声音的争论
there was kind of some debate over the sound
我们在大桥片段之后的每个片段的
that we found at the beginning of...
开头都发现了声音
seems like each clip after the bridge footage.
使用这个来自iZotope的合成器采样器Iris
Using this synthesizer sampler from iZotope, called Iris,
原理是你可以给它输入声音
you can basically feed it the sound and it'll map out the frequencies
它会直观地绘制出声音的频率和振幅
and amplitude of the sound visually.
当我把你们叫来的时候
So, when I called you guys in here, I was actually
我其实在想加文应该也在场的
thinking that Gavin would be in here, as well.
他是导演 我本以为他会想看的
He's the director and yeah, I would have thought he would want to see this,
这太疯狂了 有点像在证实自己的影片真实性 但是
it's pretty crazy, kind of validates him, but...
加文已经失踪9天了
Gavin have been missing for nine days.
哈！
Huh!
好吧 你准备好了吗？
Alright, so, OK. Are you rolling?
- 是的  - 好的 在我离开之前
- Yeah! - OK, so, on the way over here,
这是加文寄来的
before I left this arrived in the mail, this is from Gavin.
我没有打开它 因为我想等到
I have not opened it up because I wanted to wait until
我们在镜头前打开它 准备好了吗？
we do this on camera. Ready?
- 是的  - 好的 好的
- Yeah. - OK. Alright.
DV摄像头
DVCAM.
- 那是什么？ - 天哪
- What is that? - Holy shit!
这是...
This is, this is...
索菲亚·克兰 这是那些片段
Sophia Crane, this is from the found footage.
这是费德曼寄给她的包裹
This is the package that Feldman sent her.
不是吧
No kidding!
这是...
This is...
好吧 要么这是道具,要么就是
OK, alright, look, either this is a prop or...
哦 妈的 他怎么得到这个的？
Oh, fuck, how did he get this?
这是索菲亚后来发现的东西
Because that was the... and then the stuff that Sophia found with the, you know,
她说这是故事板 概念艺术之类的
she was like storyboard, storyboard, concept art.
- 这一定是假的 - 从哪来的？
- This is gotta be fake. - Where is it coming from?
- 我不知道  - 我觉得是加文自己弄的
- I don't know. - I thought it was Gavin.
地图上都没有什么葛林公司
Gingo Corp's not even showing up on the map,
在马里兰哪里都找不到 倒是有一个格林格法庭
anywhere in Maryland, there's a Gringo Court!
巧了
Coincidentally.
该不是写错了吧
Of course, it's the Ginkgo Court.
什么是他妈的格林格？
What the fuck is Gringo? Because...
嘿 听着 有时候社区的名字是会变的 街道名也会更改
Hey, look, I mean, sometimes they change communities, they change the street names...
- 还有别的吗？ - 是的
- Is anything else in there? - Yeah.
看 这是他的日记 也许能告诉我们他过去两周在做什么
See, here's his journal, so maybe it tells what he's been doing for the past two weeks.
我不知道
I don't know.
这是一个汽车旅馆的钥匙卡
This is a motel key card.
- 你们开拍了吗？ - 是的
- Are you rolling? - Yeah.
妈的 怎么回事？
A lot of survey by... Fucking, what's going on?
加文
Gavin!
管理人员还在吗？
Is the management guys still...
好 我们进去吧 我认为我们不应该在这里拍摄
Good, let's go in! I don't think we should record in here.
我们不算非法入室吧？
We're not breaking in, are we?
嗯
Yeah, right.
哦 该死
Oh, shit!
加文
Gavin!
天哪 这样不好 这是什么鬼东西
Jesus, it's not good! The hell is this?
- 肯尼 肯尼 - 怎么？
- Kenny, Kenny! - What?
- 摄像机开着的  - 天哪
- The GoPro's on. - Jesus!
你觉得他在干什么？ 这他妈的是什么？
What you think he's doing? What the fuck is this?
录下来
Recording it.
这是他的相机 里面没有内存卡
Here's his camera, there's no card inside it.
有人看到松下DVX吗？
Does anybody see the Panasonic, the DVX?
磁带？
The tapes?
一切都好吗？
Everything OK?
好的 把这个放进车里 我们要把这个带走
OK, cool. Put this in the car, we'll take these with us.
- 该死 - 好吧
- Shit! - OK.
他妈的 伙计 我们离开这里 我们走 我们走
Fuck, dude! Let's get out of here! Let's go, let's go!
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我不知道 真的
I don't know, seriously!
哦 他妈的  伙计
Oh, fuck, dude!
怎么了 伙计 里面是什么？
What is it, man, what's in there?
我们不如从头开始说吧
I suggest to start from the beginning with what happened.
我们正在制作一部纪录片
OK, so, we're making a documentary.
那个开着吗？
Is that on?
你在录吗？
Are you recording it?
- 是的 -好吧
- Yes. - OK.
继续
Go ahead.
我们正在拍一部关于
We're making a documentary about
四折的纪录片
the deceased.
卡尔 录像呢？
Carl, where's the footage?
磁带在哪？
Where are the tapes?
在我车里
In my car.
我们是否应该向警方展示一下
Do you think, should we show the police
我们拍摄的内容和其他的东西呢？
the footage on the camera and everything?
- 不 不 - 为什么不？
- No, no. - Why not?
他们可能会把它拿走
They might take it away.
他们会把磁带拿走的
They'll take the tapes,
他们想要磁带 他们需要磁带
they want the tapes, they need the tapes.
带子 听着 鞋盒里的带子
The tapes, look, the tapes in the shoebox
和这里发生的事 一点关系都没有
have absolutely nothing to do with what happened here.
与它无关 我们已经有了真实的场景 我们可以使用录像
Nothing to do with it, and we already have a real scene, we can use the footage.
我说的是我们刚刚拍的镜头
I'm talking about the footage on my camera that we just shot,
我们不应该把它给警察看吗？
shouldn't we show that to the police?
是的 但是 如果我们向警方证明
Yeah, but, if we show that to the police
它会显示卡尔发现了这些磁带
it'll show that Carl found the tapes
然后他们会拿走磁带的
and then they'll take the tapes.
你觉得他在做什么 那个迷你摄像机还有其他摄像机什么的
What do you think he was doing, all the GoPros and all the camera stuff, like, what...
我不住地 我认为更重要的问题是谁拿走了这些内存卡
I don't know, I think the more important question is who took the cards?
谁？ 卡不在相机里
Who? They're not in the cameras...
- 十年后我们就会知道了  - 什么？
- So we'll find out in ten years! - What?
十年后录像就会被他人找到
That's when the footage will be found!
我昨晚很早就睡了
I went to bed early last night.
我太累了 就像你生病前一样
I was so tired, kind of like you are right before you're getting sick.
我梦见我走到隧道里 我凝视着
I dreamt I went to the tunnel and I was staring down,
就在午夜
right at midnight.
每个人都说它很难 但我认为很容易
Everyone says it's so hard, but I thought it was so easy.
然后我盯了一个小时
And when I stared for an hour,
他出现了
he appeared
然后我醒了 我意识到这不是一个梦
and then I woke up and I realized it wasn't a dream!
它离我家有十英里远
It's ten miles from my house
我不知道我是怎么到那儿的
and I don't know how I got there!
好吧 我来和你讲讲这条隧道
Alright, I'll tell you about this tunnel...
哦 妈的
Oh, fuck!
老实说 这不是我们想要的结果
Let's be honest here, this is not what we thought this was going to be,
我们现在是想要探寻真相
and now we're trying to make something out of it.
听着 不是所有的纪录片都一定要有什么结果的
Listen, not all documentaries, not all projects come together.
这就是其中一个例子 没能成功的例子
This is one of those examples, it just didn't, it didn't pan out.
所以你的意思是我们要对眼前这个精彩的故事视而不见吗？
So you're saying we don't have a compelling story to cut together here, we don't have...
这个故事没有尽头 我们只是傻傻地站在铁轨上罢了
There's, there's no end to this story other than us standing here on the tracks.
这个故事没有结局 因为这只是个开始
There's no end of this story because it's all, this is the beginning.
- 你明白吗？ - 什么？
- You understand? - What?
我们有带子 对吧？
We have the tapes, right?
然后未知工作室发现了音频的事情 是吧？
Then there's what Studio Unknown found, OK?
他们发现了那个声音异常
They found that sound anomaly.
我们没有加进去 加文也没有
We didn't put that there, Gavin didn't put that there.
沃德罗发现了哪个镜头 眼睛里的倒映
With what Wardlaw found, OK, with the reflection in the eye,
我们也可以选择把纪录片投放出去
and I don't know we put this documentary out there
其他人可以把它带到下一个阶段
and other people can take it to the next step!
- 这仅仅是个开始  - 你在自相矛盾
- This is just the beginning. - You're contradicting yourself!
- 我没有自相矛盾 - 你刚才说
- I'm not contradicting myself! - You just said we're not trying
我们不是要像真实的故事那样呈现我们 现在你却要像这样呈现
to present us like a real story, and now you are trying to present it like this.
我试着像真实故事一样讲述加文·约克的遭遇
I am trying to present this like the real story of what happened to Gavin York.
因为我们想要讲述加文的故事
And because we're trying to tell Gavin's story,
其中包含的这些因素是他故事的一部分
these component factors that are included in there are part of his story,
他身上发生的事情的一部分
part of what happened to him.
我不是说这是真的
I'm not saying it's real,
我只是说
I'm just saying that
什么样的白痴才会无视这个
what kind of a fucking idiot just drops it!
埃里克 那你相信那个眨眼人是真的吗？
Erik, do you believe that the Blinkman is real?
我叫索菲亚·克兰 今天是2004年3月3日
My name is Sophia Crane. It's March 3rd, 2004.
我是一个电影系学生 这是我的毕业论文
I'm a film student and this is my senior thesis.
我不知道我还能活多久
I don't know how much longer I'm going to be alive,
所以我请求找到这个的人
so I ask whoever find this,
请把这次最后片段
please apply the first and second halves
前半段和后半段
of this final interview
拼接到我的电影的开头和结局
to the beginning and end of my film.
我不知道该去哪里弄
I don't know where to make the cut.
这是偷窥狂汤姆的故事 以及我去寻找他的故事
This is the story of Peeping Tom and how I went looking for him.
请把这个给我的父母看
Please show this to my parents.
我不知道我还能坚持多久不眨眼
I don't know how much longer I can go without blinking,
但我想我找到了打败他的方法
but I think I found a way to beat him.
那个盯着太阳看的女孩只是失去了视力
The girl who stared into the sun
她还得眨眼睛
she only lost her sight, she still had to blink.
每个人都不得不眨眼
Everyone blinks.
他就在这里 戏谑我 我要尝试最后一招
It's right here, taunting me, try one last thing.
他们说你骗不了偷窥狂汤姆
They say you can't cheat Peeping Tom.
但是我想我找到了在他的游戏中打败他的方法
But I think I found the way to beat him at his own game!
字幕OCR 压制lengshan310
加文·约克 电影制作人
2015年5月8日 巴尔的摩 MD
房屋出售
伊芙·亨克尔勒 加文的丈母娘
阿米莉亚·加文 加文的太太
下面这段是克兰和费德曼的电影粗略剪辑 由加文发现的
这段视频是用黑白胶片在标准的分层视频上录制的 使用了两种不同相机
保留身份 巴尔的摩警察
大卫·斯特尔 电影评论家 作家
史蒂夫·耶格尔 神圣垃圾导演
安迪·沃德劳 寻找大脚怪 剪辑
玛格丽特·佩里·艾丽希 灵感的选择追踪 总裁
与未知工作室的后期音频会议
凯文·希尔 合作伙伴 音效主管    詹米·霍尔根 执行合伙人
马特·戴维斯 合伙人 监督音效编辑
马特·雷克 作家与编辑
大卫·斯特里特 电影评论家 作家
史蒂夫·耶格尔 导演
马特·雷克 作家与编辑 美国怪异系列丛书
莫妮卡·巴特科 心理学家
艾德亚多·桑奇兹 女巫布莱尔导演
以下据说是索菲亚用她的掌上录像机录下的现场报道
记着联系的马里兰州新闻机构并未发表评论
加文与摄制组停止了近一周的沟通
晚上十一点隧道见 带上组员
摄影机停止了拍摄 但埃里克的麦克风还开着
安迪·沃德劳 在发现的录像中有异常后联系了摄制组
马特·戴维斯 合伙人 监督音效编辑
验尸报告显示加文·约克死于心脏衰竭
终年39岁